<i>Yet another quick knockout for</i> <i>Mason Dixon, almost perfunctory.</i>
梅森·迪克逊再次轻易击倒对方  毫无悬念
<i>The fans let him know</i> <i>how they feel about it.</i>
观众对此非常不满
<i>Hide the women and children.</i> <i>This could get ugly.</i>
快保护女人和孩子  看来场面就要失控了
<i>This crowd does nothing to hide</i> <i>its anger over this latest debacle.</i>
观众们毫不掩饰他们对此的愤怒
<i>The fans are mad as hell.</i> <i>They don't want to take it anymore.</i>
拳迷们近乎疯狂了  他们不想再忍了
<i>They seem to be blaming Dixon,</i> <i>a good fighter, for the decline...</i>
迪克逊非常优秀  但观众认为…
<i>... not only of the heavyweight-division</i> <i>guys, but of the entire sport.</i>
他不仅导致了重量级拳手的没落  更影响了整个拳坛
<i>They're actually pelting...</i>
他们甚至开始…
<i>... the undefeated heavyweight</i> <i>champion of the world with ice.</i>
向这位战无不胜的重量级冠军投掷冰块
<i>Maybe this angry, visceral reaction</i> <i>will pressure Dixon to fight someone...</i>
也许这怒火和过激的行为  可以迫使迪克逊迎战…
<i>... who can fight back for a change.</i> <i>If there's somebody out there.</i>
一位实力相当的对手  如果真有这种人的话
<i>All of boxing is hoping for a warrior</i> <i>who thrills us with his passion.</i>
整个拳坛都在寻找令人为之一振的热血斗士
Time goes by too fast.
时间过得可真快
Yeah? Not fast enough.
不  它还不够快
- Your kid should've been here. - That's all right.
- 你儿子应该来的  - 没关系
- No, it ain't all right. - The kid gets a little busy sometimes.
- 怎么没关系？- 他工作有时很忙
He don't get that busy.
就算他再忙也应该来的
Let's not talk about it here, okay? You're coming tonight, right?
别在这儿说这些了  好么？你今晚过来坐坐吧？
I'm working. I took the tour the last three years.
我要上班  这三年净跟着你到处回忆了
I know, but it's the anniversary.
我知道  但今天是她的忌日
Fine. You got my word.
好吧  我来就是了
I appreciate it, thank you. I owe you, Paulie.
太好了  谢谢你  我欠你个人情  保利
Yo, Robert. What's going on? Where have you been? You're late.
罗伯特  怎么回事？你去哪里了？你迟到了
No. I don't wanna hear this. Look, your job performance...
不  我不要听这些解释
...is nowhere near good enough to be pulling this.
听着  你的工作表现真是太糟糕了
I don't give a damn who your father is. You understand me?
我可不管你老爷子是谁  你听明白了吗？
- All right. Now get out of here. - Okay.
- 好 现在给我工作去  - 好
Thank you, sir.
谢谢  先生
Yo, Robert. Yo.
嗨  罗伯特
- Hey, Rocky. - Hey.
- 嘿 洛奇  - 嘿
- Hey, how you doing? - Hey.
- 嘿 你好吗？- 嘿
What's up, champ?
怎么了  拳王？
- You caught me off guard. - I know.
- 你不通知我就来找我  - 我知道
I wanted to catch you before you got busy.
我想在你不太忙的时候  来见见你
Yeah, it gets busy up there.
对  办公室挺忙的
- So how you doing? Yeah? - Real good. Yeah.
- 最近好吗？- 很好
- Yo, Rock! - Yeah, how you doing?
- 嗨 洛奇！- 嗯 你好
Yeah, real good.
是啊  真的很好
Listen, you wanna go out and get some coffee?
那么  咱们出去喝杯咖啡吧？
I'm kind of behind. Maybe later?
我要迟到了  晚些好么？
Yeah. That'd be great. You ought to come by the restaurant tonight.
嗯  那好吧  不如今晚到我的餐厅来吧
I can have something made special for you.
我可以让他们专门给你做点好菜
Tonight I can't. I got plans. A few of the guys get together.
今晚不行  我打算和一些朋友聚聚
- Did I do something wrong? - What do you mean?
- 我做错什么了吗？- 什么意思？
Well, I don't know exactly what I mean...
我也不知道确切指什么
...but I just think, like, when I come here, you don't feel so comfortable.
就是觉得  我一过来  你就很不自然
And I certainly don't wanna do that.
我当然不想这样
- Well, you throw a big shadow. - A big shadow?
- 这么说吧 你的影响力太大  - 影响力？
You're not gonna get anything done down here, Robert.
还不赶紧去工作  罗伯特
Well, if you're not gonna introduce me, I will. Hi, I'm William Tomilson.
你不介绍的话  我就自己来吧  嘿  我是威廉·汤米尔森
- How you doing? - Your son works for me.
- 你好  - 你儿子很不幸要为我工作
- It's a good job. - Yeah.
- 这工作很好  - 是啊
I've told Robert about 20 times that I wanted to meet you.
我和罗伯特提过很多次  希望能见见你
You're pretty busy, which isn't a bad thing.
你真忙啊  那样很充实
- I get a little tied up. - Grab a shot, will you?
- 我是挺忙的  - 帮我们照张相吧？
I may not get this chance again. Old warhorses have to stick together.
下次不一定有机会了  我们这些老兵们应该团结一致
- The old horses, yeah. - I'll tell you.
- 老兵 说得对  - 告诉你
- Good thing it's not your left. - This makes you popular with people.
- 还好不是你的左拳  - 这张照片会让你火起来的
- One, two, three. - Finally, we get to meet.
- 一 二 三  - 我们终于见到面了
I gotta get going. It was nice to meet you face to face.
我得走了  很高兴亲眼见到你
You take care of yourself. Robert, I'll see you later.
你多保重  罗伯特  回头见
I gotta get going. I'll change my plans for tonight.
我得走了  我改变今晚的计划了
That'd be great. I'm looking forward to it.
那太好了  我等你过来
- How you doing? - Okay.
- 多保重  - 好的
- Okay. - All right.
- 嗯  - 好的
And do not let those numbers drive you crazy.
不也因为那些数字而心烦
- Too late. - Use an eraser, get rid of all of them.
- 太迟了  - 用橡皮把它们全擦掉
- Yo, Rock. - Hey, guys.
- 洛奇  - 嘿 朋友们
- Hey, Rock. - Hey, how you doing?
- 嘿 洛奇  - 嘿 你好吗？
There you go.
给你
It'll be about 10 tenths. You guys take care, okay? You got it.
我要十块小奶酪  一会儿拿  我先走了  记好
I'll try a few of these later on.
过会儿我来买些这个
- It's good for baking. - How much...?
- 很适合烘烤  - 多少钱？
- Yo, Paul, what's the cost? - 58.40, sir.
- 保罗 多少钱？- 58 块 4
All right, take it out of that. I trust you.
好  钱拿去  我相信你
- How you doing? - You're too generous.
- 你好吗？- 你真是太慷慨了
Not a problem.
不客气
How you guys doing?
你们好
How we doing, Isabel?
怎么样了  伊莎贝尔？
Okay, except for the freebie reading the Bible.
还好  除了啃《圣经》吃白食的那个家伙
- He's okay. - Just because you fought him...
- 他没关系  - 就算你们打过拳
...don't mean you gotta feed him. He doesn't look like a fighter.
也不能喂他一辈子  他看起来不像个拳手
Spider Rico could hit.
斯柏德·里克是很强的
- Listen, how's your stomach? - It's okay.
- 你的宝宝怎么样了？- 还好
If you keep rubbing olive oil on your stomach...
坚持往肚子上抹橄榄油
...your kid's gonna be born very strong.
孩子生下来会很强壮的
- Okay, Rocky. Whatever you say. - No, really.
- 好吧 洛奇 随便你怎么说吧  - 这是真的
- Yo, how you doing, Spider? - God bless you, Rocky.
- 最近好吗 斯柏德？- 上帝保佑你 洛奇
Thanks.
谢谢
How you guys doing?
伙计们  你们好吗？
Jose, can you make something special for my kid who's coming tonight?
何塞  今晚我儿子要来  你能为他做点特别的吗？
No problemo.
没问题
Good. I appreciate it.
好  我很感激
<i>Back and forth, back and forth,</i> <i>give and take.</i>
进进退退  防守  进攻
And then I went in there like an animal and threw him into the corner...
然后我像头野兽般冲向他  把他逼向绳角…
...and I unloaded everything I had. Hook, hook, hook, left, left, left.
然后我使出浑身解数  勾拳  勾拳  左勾拳  右勾拳
But Creed, he kept busting me back pretty good...
但是奎迪一直凶猛的攻击我的背部
...and the agony began to pile up.
…我开始忍受痛苦煎熬
Then I heard the best sound that I ever heard in my life...
那时我听到了我有生以来最美好的声音
- The bell. - That's right, the bell.
- 结束的铃声  - 没错 就是这个铃声
I ain't never been so tired, and I'm sitting in my corner.
我瘫坐在角落里  从没感受到如此疲倦
I'm trying to figure out how to survive the last round...
我试着去想如何熬过最后一个回合…
...when Mickey leans into my ear and says:
当米奇靠近我的耳朵  和我说
"Come on, get out there and fight this guy hard, you bum.
"振作起来  狠狠的揍那家伙  孬种"
You gotta be first. You gotta be first." I said, "Yo, Mick, if I could...
"你必须赢  你必须赢" 我说 "米奇 如果我可以…"
- "I would." ...I would."
- "我一定会"  - 最后我做到了
The end.
就这样
<i>Yet another quick knockout for</i> <i>Mason Dixon, almost perfunctory.</i>
"梅森·迪克逊再次轻易击倒对方  毫无悬念"
<i>The fans let him know</i> <i>how they feel about it.</i>
"观众对此非常不满"
<i>They're actually pelting...</i>
"他们甚至开始…"
<i>... the undefeated heavyweight</i> <i>champion of the world with ice.</i>
"向这位战无不胜的重量级冠军投掷冰块"
Hello, Adrian's. Yeah?
你好  艾黛丽安餐厅  什么？
Tell him you can't make it? Yeah, I'll give him the message.
告诉他你不能来了？好的  我会转告他
I just kept hearing Mickey's voice in my head over and over again.
我脑子里一遍一遍听到米奇对我说的话
I just dug down, and before you know it...
我只是倒了下去  之前你知道…
...it was toe to toe and it was... Excuse me.
我们针锋相对… 抱歉
Your son said he can't make it. He said he'll take a rain check. Okay?
你儿子说他不能来了  改天再约
<i>Look at these birds.</i>
这些小鸟
<i>Don't these birds look like candy?</i> <i>Flying candy?</i>
看起来就像糖果  会飞的糖果？
<i>Hey, birdie,</i> <i>you wanna fly me home?</i>
嘿  鸟儿  你想带我飞回家吗？
You need somebody to walk you home?
需要人送你回家吗？
<i>No?</i>
不需要？
It's a cold night. We need a few laughs in our life. What do you think? Maybe?
今晚很冷  人生需要多一点的笑声  你觉得呢？
<i>Maybe? Maybe?</i>
也许？也许？
<i>Okay. Let's get out of here, okay?</i>
好了  咱们走吧  好吗？
That place ain't changed much from last year.
这地方和去年没什么不同
Are we done?
我们走吧？
Hey, how you doing, Mick?
嘿  你还好吗  米奇？
That sign is falling apart, Paulie.
招牌快掉下来了  保利
The whole world is falling apart. Look at us.
整个世界都要倒下了  瞧瞧我们
Don't talk crazy, Paulie.
别胡说  保利
You know, I think if you live someplace long enough, you are that place.
你知道  我觉得如果在某个地方住得够久  就会融入其中
I ain't no talking building.
我不是指的建筑
Come on, it's getting late, Rocko.
走吧  天色不早了  洛奇
I get a headache from this train.
这火车的声音让我头疼
I remember when she was standing there...
我记得当时她站在这里…
...all nervous and shy, with this little smile.
紧张和羞怯  带着一丝微笑
And all I wanted her to do was trust me.
我所要她做的仅仅是相信我
She did.
她做到了
- She did. - You done?
- 她做到了  - 你有完没完？
- How long are we staying here? - Not long.
- 我们在这呆多久？- 一会就行
Well, I'm glad they tore this ice rink down.
我很高兴他们把溜冰场拆了
Come on.
别这样
You heard me. I'm happy they tore it apart.
你听到了  我很高兴他们把它拆了
First time I walked your sister across this ice, we was over there.
我第一次陪你妹妹滑冰的时候  就在那边
She was nervous, but I wasn't so great on the blades either.
她很紧张  不过我也不太会滑冰
Ice is stupid. People standing on ice are more stupid.
冰很无聊  站在冰上滑的人更无聊
And over there, when she was falling...
还有那里  她要摔倒时…
...and my hand grabbed her...
我抓住了她…
...and I got her arm through that coat, I could feel it.
隔着大衣抓住了她  我感觉到
Electric.
爱的火花
You said the same thing last year, Rock.
去年你也是那么说的  洛奇
Did I?
是吗？
- So you better develop your brain.
所以要好好利用头脑
- You're left-handed. - Absolutely.
- 因为你是左撇子  - 当然
Come on, Rock. Let's go.
快点  洛奇  我们走吧
We're done. There's no place to sit down around here.
走吧  这周围连坐的地方都没有
It's all right.
没关系
It ain't all right! It's depressing and freaking cold!
什么没关系！这儿又压抑又冷得要死！
What's the matter with you, Paulie?
你怎么了  保利？
You're living backwards, Rocko!
你还活在过去之中  洛奇！
Change the channel from yesterday! Yesterday wasn't so great!
人不能总留恋过去！过去并没那么好！
- It was to me. - Not to me!
- 对我来说很好  - 我的不好！
You treated her good. You had the good times.
你对她很好  你们有过美好的时光
I treated her bad. I don't have to think about this.
我对她不好  所以我不想回忆这些
She always loved you, Paulie.
她一直很爱你  保利
Sorry, Rocko, I can't do this no more.
抱歉  洛奇  我不想再回忆了
Can I help you?
有什么需要帮忙的？
No, no, I used to come down to this place a long time ago.
不  不  很久以前我常来这里
I was just looking around. No big deal.
我只是四处看看  没什么事
Can I get you a drink?
要喝的吗？
- All right. Maybe just a short beer. - Okay.
- 好吧 来一小瓶啤酒  - 好
Go. Go on.
去  去啊
Yeah, go on. Get him to buy a round.
对啊  去呀  让他买单
Get him to buy a round. Go.
让他买单  去啊
Get him to... He's got it. He's spending money.
让那家伙买单  他有钱
Listen, I don't mean to cross the line or anything...
那个  不是我想多管闲事什么的…
...but I read about your wife's passing a few years back.
我看到报道说你妻子前几年去世了
Yeah, it was woman cancer.
是的  癌症
Yeah. I always heard she was a nice person.
我总听人说她人很好
Yeah, the best.
对  很好
- Do I know you? - We met a long time ago.
- 我认识你吗？- 我们很久以前见过
We did?
我们见过？
When I was a kid, you walked me home.
我还是个孩子时  你送我回家
- I did? - Told me to stop smoking and things.
- 是吗？- 劝我戒烟什么的
Stop smoking...
戒烟…
Are you Little Marie that used to hang out at that Atomic Hoagie shop?
你就是那个总在三明治店里玩的小玛丽？
Yeah, that's right.
对  就是我
Yeah, now I remember. I walked you home.
我想起来了  我送你回家
When you got there, you turned around and said, "Screw you, creepo."
当你到家后  转身对我说 "去你的  小人"
- I didn't say that. - Yeah, you did.
- 我没那么说  - 不 你说了
- You sure? - Great insults last a long time.
- 你确定？- 奇耻大辱 怎么会忘记
Yo! Yo, is that you? Is that really you?
嘿！是你吗？真的是你？
- How you doing? - I think he wants to drink alone.
- 你好  - 我认为他想要一个人喝酒
Well, then give him his drink, then. I ain't stopping you.
那你就把酒给他呀  我又没拦着你
What's that, your man or something? No, I don't think so.
他是你男人还是什么的？不  我看不是
Anyway, me and my friends, we're right down there.
我说  我和我的朋友坐在那儿
Think you could buy us a round? You got the money. Just one round.
你请我们喝一杯吧？来吧  你那么有钱
Hey. Thank you.
嘿  谢谢
What are you doing pushing my hand away like that?
你干嘛？你干吗这样推开我？
- What's your name? - Angie. What do you wanna know for?
- 你叫什么？- 安吉 你要知道这干吗？
- Don't be playing a fool for that guy. - A fool?
- 别为他们做傻瓜  - 傻瓜？
- Yeah. - A fool?
- 对  - 傻瓜？
I'm the fool? You're the fool, not me!
我是傻瓜？你才是傻瓜  不是我！
You got it twisted. You're the fool. I'm a person, just like you.
你弄混了  你才是傻瓜  我是个人  和你一样
You ain't no better than me. You think you're a big shot now? You're nothing.
你不比我好多少  你自以为很了不起啊？你根本不是
You ain't no better than me. No better!
你没有比我好多少  没有！
Glad you dropped in?
真不该来吧？
I think the neighborhood is changing a little.
我觉得邻居有了点小变化
- What was that all about? - I don't know. Forget about it.
- 刚才怎么了？- 不知道 算了 没什么
I'm gonna lock up, so if you wanna take off, I'll tally everything up.
我要关门了  如果你想走  我会加一下总账
- Yeah, thanks. - How you doing, Rock?
- 好的 谢谢  - 你好吗 洛奇？
I'm good, thanks.
还不错  谢谢
- You live around here? - About eight blocks from here.
- 你住在附近？- 离这八个街区
Eight blocks.
八个街区
You need a lift?
要搭车么？
All right.
好的
Did you ever get married?
你结过婚吗？
- Yeah, sort of. - Sort of?
- 算结过吧  - 算结过？
- Yeah, well, he took off. - Poof, just like that?
- 对 他走了  - 他 "嗖" 的一下就不见了？
Yeah, just like that.
对  "嗖"的一下
- You sort of have any kids? - Yeah, I got one kid.
- 那你有孩子吗？- 有 我有一个孩子
Yeah? Me too. Me too. Wonderful boy.
是么？我也是  很棒的男孩
Hey, tough guy! What's the matter, you can't buy a round?
嘿  大块头！请我们喝一杯都不行吗？
The girl was being nice to your dumb ass.
她对你这个傻瓜这么友善
- What you doing with that pig? - Think you can disrespect us?
- 那头母猪有什么好？- 你以为就能对我们这么无礼？
- She ain't nothing but a jealous bitch! - Come on back!
- 她只不过是个妓女而已！- 你给我回来！
Hey, don't listen to them.
嘿  别听他们的
Both of youse, you ain't no better than me.
你们两个都是  你也没有比我好多少！
Come over here, you'll get your head kicked in around here.
有种过来  我会踢爆你的脑袋
- You punch-drunk, goofy bastard. - You ain't no big shot, look at you.
- 你这杂种 被打傻了吧？- 你不再是大牌了 瞧瞧你
You ain't even got a car to take that pig home.
开这种破车  还带那只母猪回家
You all right?
还好吗？
Yeah.
还好
What are you doing? Don't get out. It's all right.
你要干吗？别出去  我没事的
No, Little Marie. It ain't all right.
不  小玛丽  这事大了
- Yo. - What?
- 嘿  - 怎么样？
I'll tell you what. Get inside.
我告诉你怎么样  你们进去
- You get inside. Yeah, you. - Hey, leave him alone!
- 到屋里去 就你  - 嘿 放开他！
- Yo, man! - See it?
- 啊 大哥！- 你看她？
- You see that? You see that? - Yeah. All right.
- 看见了吗？- 看见了
- What do you say? - I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
- 应该说什么？- 对不起 对不起！
Get a job!
干正事去！
That guy sends his apologies.
那家伙向你道歉了
Okay.
好的
Martin. Martin. Yo, Martin!
马丁  马丁  嘿  马丁！
I see you still got your key.
原来你还有钥匙
Yeah, I got a key. You got time to talk?
是啊  我有钥匙  有时间聊聊么？
I got a lot of time since your people let me go.
自从你的人让我走以后  我闲得很
You know I had nothing to do with that.
你知道  那和我无关
Yeah.
是啊
Yeah, we moved in about a year ago.
我们一年前搬进去的
- Yeah? - Yeah, I mean, it's only temporary.
- 是吗？- 我意思是 这只是暂时的
- Yeah, I could see that. - I'm gonna look for an apartment.
- 是的 我能看出来  - 我打算找间公寓
Apartments are nice.
公寓很好
Yeah. It is what it is, you know.
是啊  也还算过得去吧
Yeah, it is what it is.
是啊  还算过得去
This place used to be pretty nice. There's a lot of history around here.
这地方曾经很美丽  这里有着许多的往事
- Yeah. - Like down the street...
- 是啊  - 比如这条街尾
...is the Cambria Fight Club.
有家叫坎布里亚的搏击俱乐部
They used to call it the Bucket of Blood.
过去大家常叫它喋血乐园
I took some massive beatings there. But it was nice. Good memories.
我在那被打过很多次  但回忆终究是那么美好
And I heard these buildings are like, I don't know, 100, 150 years old.
我听说这些楼大概有 100 或 150 年了
If I was 150 years old, I'd be falling apart too. So it's okay, building.
如果我有 150 岁肯定要散架了  所以这些楼还不错
Does that light work?
那些灯还亮吗？
- No, it's burnt out or something. Yeah. - Yeah?
- 不亮 可能是烧坏了吧  - 是么？
Listen, thanks for the ride, and I'm sorry about those guys.
谢谢你送我  要是没遇到那群人就好了  抱歉
Some of those guys just got their brains on backwards and stuff.
没事  那群人脑子坏了  不知道自己在做些什么
- What's he doing out so late? - Is that your kid?
- 这么晚了他在外面干吗？- 那是你儿子？
Yeah. Wish he wouldn't stay out so late.
是啊  真不希望他那么晚了还在外面晃荡
- Amazing. - Yeah, what's that?
- 真神奇  - 什么神奇？
Last time I seen you, you was a kid...
上次见你时  你还是个孩子
...and now you officially got one of your own.
…现在连小孩都那么大了
It's amazing.
多神奇啊
You know, he sort of resembles you. He's got that big Irish hair.
他长得挺像你的  长着爱尔兰的金发
Yeah, it's the other one.
不  是另一个
- Yeah? - His father was from Jamaica.
- 是么？- 他父亲是牙买加人
Jamaica? European.
牙买加？欧洲吧？
Was you on a cruise ship or something?
游轮上认识的还是什么？
- No, not really. - What's his name?
- 不 不是  - 他叫什么？
- Steps. Short for Stevenson. - Makes sense.
- 斯泰普斯 全名是史蒂文森  - 很相配
Does he look mad at me, or is it maybe the angle I'm standing at?
他是在瞪我吗？还是我站的角度有问题？
No. He's a good kid.
没有  他是个好孩子
- You wanna meet him? - It's getting kind of late.
- 想见见他么？- 不了 已经很晚了
- I got so many things to do. - Yeah, yeah, I understand.
- 我还有很多事要忙  - 是啊 我明白
Thanks again for the ride and everything else.
再次谢谢你送我回来  还有那件事
I'll see you.
再见
Hey, Steps, come on. Let's go. Say good night to your friend.
嘿  斯泰普斯  回家吧  和朋友说晚安
What are you doing out in the cold with no hat on?
这么冷的天在外面也不戴顶帽子？
- Did you get something to eat? - Yeah, I already ate.
- 饭吃了么？- 是的 已经吃过了
All right.
好吧
- You're late, you know. - I can take care of myself.
- 你迟到了 知道么？- 我可以自己照顾好自己
Yo, Little Marie!
嘿  小玛丽！
Ain't you gonna introduce me to your kid?
你不打算介绍你儿子给我认识吗？
- How you doing, Steps? - What's up?
- 你好吗 斯泰普斯？- 什么事？
Listen, I got this place, this restaurant, nice little eatery not too far from here.
我有一家小餐馆  一家不错的小餐馆  离这儿不远
What's all this junk? Got a tissue.
什么垃圾东西？一张餐巾纸
Sometimes I feel like a kangaroo, all the stuff in my pocket, you know.
有时候我像只袋鼠似的  口袋里什么都有
Here you go. I got a card, there it is.
找到了  我给你一张名片
And if you ever get a chance, it'd be great...
那个  有机会的话…
...if both of youse come down there and eat.
欢迎你来我的餐馆吃饭
It'd be great, free. You know. Anyway, I'll leave it over there... Here.
或者随便什么  我请客  那么我就把它放在… 这儿
I'll leave it on the steps. Steps.
【注】斯泰普斯英语中有台阶的意思。
See you later.
回头见
Come on, let's go.
来吧  我们走
<i>You've known what's best for you</i> <i>since you were 10.</i>
你 10 岁独自来到这儿时
Since you walked in here alone.
就知道什么最适合自己
Got everything money can buy...
你得了钱能买的一切…
...except what it can't.
除了买不到的
It's pride. Pride is what got your ass out of here.
那就是骄傲  就是骄傲让你离开了这里
Losing is what brung you back.
失败让你再次回来
But people like you, they need to be tested. Need a challenge.
像你这种人需要的是考验  需要的是挑战
That ain't gonna happen. Ain't nothing out there.
那不可能  根本没有合适的对手
There's always somebody out there. Always.
人外有人  天外有天  一定会有的
When that time comes and you find something...
每一天  某人站在你面前…
...standing in front of you that ain't running...
不逃避  不退缩
...that ain't backing up, hitting on you, and you're too damn tired to breathe...
猛烈地击打着你  你被累到喘不过气来
You find that situation on you, that's good.
当这个情况发生在你身上时  那是好事
Because that's baptism under fire.
因为那是 "战火" 的洗礼
You get through that, you find the only kind of respect...
你度过了那一关  你会认识到…
...that matters in this damn world:
这世界上唯一的一种尊敬
Self-respect.
自尊
Thanks, Martin. I appreciate that.
谢谢你  马丁  我很感激
Now, what can the champ do for you?
现在  我能为你做点什么呢？
You can give me some of that money you got.
你可以给我点钱啊
- You know, I like you, Martin. - But not that much.
- 你知道 我喜欢你 马丁  - 但还没那么喜欢
Exactly.
正如你所言
How about a picture with the kid? All right?
可以和我的儿子照张相么？
Sure.
当然
Here, son, hold up your fist. Makes you look more hazardous.
孩子  举起拳头  这样显得更勇猛
- There you go. - Thanks, Rock.
- 你们继续  - 谢谢 洛奇
Enjoy your meal.
用餐愉快
- He's a nice guy, isn't he? - Rocky?
- 他人不错吧？- 洛奇？
- Yeah. - Spider just went downstairs.
- 是的  - 斯柏德刚下楼去了
- I don't know if that's all right. - What's he doing?
- 我不知道那样是否可以  - 他要干什么？
I don't know. That's your friend.
不知道  他是你朋友
Yo, Spider!
嘿  斯柏德！
- Let me do some dishes. I feel better. - Come on. You're my guest.
- 让我洗些盘子 我也好受些  - 别这样 你是客人
- Let me do something. - Keep eating. Guests do that.
- 让我做点什么吧  - 来这儿吃饭 客人嘛
Don't make me fight you again. Last time you got lucky.
不要逼我再和你打  上次只是你走运
Lucky? Okay.
走运？好吧
Jesus wants me to work.
耶稣让我工作
- Yo, Rocky. - Yeah?
- 嘿 洛奇  - 什么？
You've got guests.
你有客人
Don't get too wet, okay?
别弄得太湿  好吧？
Glad Jesus didn't ask you to cook.
幸好耶稣没让你做饭
You kept the card.
你留着名片了
Yeah, I kept the card.
是啊  我留下了
- Why don't you sit down? - Yeah, sure.
- 为什么不先坐下呢？- 好 当然
Because, you know what, I walk in there, I say good morning, I do this:
知道我怎么做么  我走过去问个好  然后这样
<i>Tonight, boxing once again.</i>
今晚  又有一场拳击较量
<i>Two contrasting styles</i> <i>in almost every way.</i>
两位风格炯异的拳王
Hey, can you turn this up? Turn this up, please.
嘿  能大点声吗？拜托大点声
<i>Who was the best of all time?</i> <i>If two athletes from different eras...</i>
谁才是有史以来最棒的拳手呢？如果两位不同时代的拳王
<i>... could compete against one another,</i> <i>who would come out on top?</i>
…能够同场竞技  谁能登上世界的顶峰呢？
<i>Given the same rules, using the same</i> <i>equipment, who was the greatest?</i>
同样的规则  同样的装备  谁才是最好的呢？
<i>We feed our facts</i> <i>into the computer.</i>
我们把数据输入电脑
<i>They weigh in on who they</i> <i>think will reign supreme...</i>
他们全盛时期的体重
<i>... while fielding the comments of our</i> <i>illustrious panel of sportswriters.</i>
还有我们资深体育版记者的评价
Champ!
冠军！
- Yo, champ! - Yeah?
- 嘿 冠军！- 嗯？
Come check out this trash they're talking about you, man!
过来看看这些废物  他们在谈论着你  伙计！
- What you talking about? - Come check this out. Hurry up.
- 他们说什么了？- 过来看下 快点
<i>Tonight, the former two-time</i> <i>heavyweight champion...</i>
今晚  曾经的两次最重量级拳王
<i>... from Philadelphia, Rocky Balboa.</i>
来自费城的洛奇·巴尔博亚
<i>All right, Chuck Johnson,</i> USA <i>Today?</i>
有请《今日美国》的查克·约翰逊
<i>There's no question that</i> <i>Rocky Balboa fought tougher fights...</i>
毫无疑问  洛奇·巴尔博亚在拳台上打过很多硬仗
<i>... during a tougher era in boxing.</i>
在那个艰苦的时代
<i>You look at Mason Dixon</i> <i>in his career...</i>
你们看梅森·迪克逊的职业生涯…
<i>... he's basically been</i> <i>spoon-fed his opponents.</i>
他基本上被他的对手宠坏了
<i>No question in my mind.</i> <i>Not only does Rocky win...</i>
在我看来  毫无疑问  洛奇不仅获胜
<i>... but he wins knockout.</i>
而且他将击倒对手
Rocky!
洛奇！
Offspring.
后代…
<i>Bernard Fernandez?</i>
伯纳德·费尔南德斯？
<i>Dixon is a victim</i> <i>of his own dominance.</i>
迪克逊是自己优势的受害者
<i>He's never been in</i> <i>real knockdown-dragout brawls.</i>
他从没经历过真正激烈的持久战
<i>He never had to dig down</i> <i>to rally back.</i>
从没有被放倒后重整旗鼓的经历
<i>If he tries to dig down</i> <i>against Balboa...</i>
如果他想要放倒巴尔博亚
<i>... he'll find he doesn't have</i> <i>a big enough shovel.</i>
他会发现他还没有足够大的铲子
<i>I clearly give it to Balboa.</i>
我很明确支持巴尔博亚
What happened to you? What happened to you?
你怎么回事？你怎么了？
<i>Boxing historian</i> <i>Burt Randolph Sugar.</i>
拳击历史学家  波特·兰道夫·苏加
<i>Dixon has fought cream puffs.</i> <i>We don't know what he's made of.</i>
迪克逊只打过懦夫  很难得知他的真正实力
<i>But both in their primes,</i> <i>you gotta factor in...</i>
但是在他们的颠峰期  我们必须承认这个事实…
<i>... Dixon's unbelievable speed...</i>
迪克逊有着不可思议的速度…
<i>... his slashing offense.</i> <i>He cuts Balboa to bits.</i>
尖锐的进攻  他会把巴尔博亚切成肉片
<i>No doubt. Dixon wins all the way.</i>
毫无疑问  迪克逊会轻松获胜
<i>Here's where our subjectivity ends.</i> <i>Let's see what the computer says.</i>
主观猜测到此结束  让我们看看计算机的模拟
<i>Dixon unloads on Balboa. Rocky has</i> <i>no answer. Balboa is eating jabs.</i>
梅森不断地冲击洛奇  洛奇无法还手  洛奇连吃几记刺拳
- What time is it? - Mason time.
- 现在什么时间？- 梅森时间
<i>Now Dixon is done. He is reeling.</i> <i>He is almost out on his feet!</i>
梅森完蛋了  他两腿发抖  看来马上就要倒下了！
<i>Balboa turning up the heat.</i> <i>Pounds him across the ring.</i>
洛奇乘胜追击  几乎要把他打出拳台
<i>Boy, he's bit off more than he</i> <i>can chew this time. Believe it.</i>
我相信他快坚持不住了  看吧
<i>Oh, a murderous right hook!</i> <i>And Dixon is out on his feet.</i>
一记致命的右勾拳！迪克逊站不住了
<i>He is out cold as he</i> <i>crumbles to the canvas.</i>
他失去了知觉  摔倒在拳台上
<i>And it is Balboa who has won...</i>
胜利者是巴尔博亚
Ladies and gentlemen, Baby Rocky. Baby Rocky.
女士们  先生们  这是小洛奇  小洛奇
I'm glad you liked the food. If you heat that up, it's pretty good in the morning.
我很高兴你能喜欢吃这些菜
Yeah, thanks, man.
谢谢  伙计
Nice kid. I hope this music ain't giving you a headache. I like this old stuff.
好孩子  你听这音乐不会头疼吧？我喜欢这些老歌
No, I like it. It's nice.
不  我很喜欢  很好听
Well, good. Good.
那就好  好吧
Yo, you think Steps wants a job? Make a few bucks on the weekend?
嘿  你儿子想打工吗？周末赚点零用钱？
It's good making your own G's. My kid stashed a few bucks doing that.
自己动手丰衣足食  我儿子就打工赚了点钱
Why are you being so nice?
你为什么对我们这么好？
I don't want you to think nothing's off, you know.
我没什么别的意思
My wife, she's gone, but she ain't. You know what I mean?
真的  我太太不在了  但我爱她  懂吗？
Yeah, well, I wasn't thinking that. Believe me.
不  我没有那么想  真的
- No? Then what was you thinking? - No.
- 是吗？那你的意思是？- 没什么
That you don't owe us nothing. What are you doing?
你又不欠我们什么  为什么要…
Be patient.
听好了
Now...
的确…
...I don't owe you nothing, but why do you gotta...
我不欠你什么  可谁说…
...owe something to get...?
得欠了  才能…
Bingo.
亮了
Why do you gotta owe something to get something, you know? Really.
谁说一定要欠你才能对你好呢  是吧？真的
I think hanging out with your kid would be nice. What do you think?
我很想带你儿子出去逛逛  你觉得呢？
I think that'd be nice.
我觉得挺好
Good. That's very nice.
很好  非常好
I'm glad you come by.
你能来玩我很高兴
It was nice watching you eat.
看着你吃东西  我很开心
Good company.
我的朋友
Yo, Little Marie. Let there be light!
嘿  小玛丽  让它亮着吧！
- You like dogs? - Dogs?
- 你喜欢狗么？- 狗？
Dogs. This is like a dog pound. It's where they keep...
狗  这像个狗的收容所
...a large variety of dogs. I used to come here all the time for sightseeing.
是收容流浪狗的地方  我过去经常来这里逛着玩
But, you know, you learn a lot talking to dogs.
你知道么  和狗说话能学到很多
- Really, you do. - Yeah, man. So...
- 真的 你可以  - 是 伙计 那么…
Hey, man, how about this one?
嘿  伙计  这只怎么样？
He don't look too friendly, my friend.
它看起来不太友善  我的朋友
Man, this is the one. Hey, boy, how you doing?
不会  这是缘分  嘿  小狗  你好吗？
Hey, what about this one here? Come here, boy.
这边这只怎么样？来  小狗
- Who, him? - Yeah, why not?
- 你说它？- 是 可以么？
Hell, no. That is one ugly dog, man.
哦  不要  这只狗好丑  伙计
I know, but it's kind of a cute ugly. If you look at it closely, the color...
我知道  但它丑得很可爱  近看的话  毛色有点像…
...it looks like old furniture, like some kind of pirate-chest thing going on.
旧式家具  又有点像海盗的藏宝箱之类的颜色
Yeah, sure, man. Hey, so how about a young one?
是啊  是啊  还是要只小的吧？
Steps, forget him. Come over here. I want you to see something.
斯泰普斯  不要那只  过来  我给你看点东西
Now, you notice what this animal is doing here? Lying in that position?
你看这只狗躺在那里  它在做什么？
He ain't doing nothing.
什么也没做
No, he's doing a lot. He ain't wasting no energy.
不  做了很多  它并没有浪费精力
Because he's dead.
因为它死了
He ain't dead. There's a lot of good mileage left on that animal.
没有  它没死  它还有很多路要走
Good food, the addition of a couple of new friends, bingo, he's back.
享受美食  交一些新朋友  好了  活过来了
- What do you think is a good name? - It's your dog. You name him.
- 你觉得起什么名字好？- 这是你的狗 你取吧
No. It's, like, a community animal. Fifty-fifty.
不  他是我们共有的  一人一半
Look, I don't know much about no dogs.
可是  我对狗不太了解
Well, it ain't that complicated.
没关系  其实没那么复杂
You pet him, you feed him, and nature takes its course.
就是拍一拍  喂一喂  然后顺其自然就行了
You know, so... Don't you wanna name an animal?
你不想给它起个名字么？
Every guy should at one time try to name an animal something.
每个人至少都应该给动物起一次名字
I don't know. Fleabag?
不知道  "睡袋" 吧？
It's catchy. It ain't original, but it's pretty good.
很好记  还行  没啥新意  但也挺好
I think you could come up with, in your young brain...
不过我觉得你这么年轻…
...something better to throw out than Fleabag.
应该能想出一个比 "睡袋" 更好的名字
Punchy. How's that?
拳头  怎么样？
- Punchy? - Yeah, Punchy.
- 拳头？- 是的 拳头
- I like it, you know. - For real?
- 我喜欢 不错  - 真的？
Yeah, for real. Punchy it is. It's easy to remember, it's not that hard to spell.
对  真的  就叫拳头吧  好记  也很容易拼
And once it's in your brain, you never forget it. Punchy. Very good.
一旦记住  永远不忘  拳头  很好
- All right, man. - Good call.
- 好吧 伙计  - 好名字
All right, Punchy. You ready to get bailed out, my friend?
好吧  拳头  你准备好要被保释了吗  我的朋友？
Okay.
好的
Hey, you know it was a joke, don't you?
嘿  你知道我是在开玩笑？
Yeah, I know. You're a very funny guy.
是的  我知道  你很幽默
Rocky?
洛奇？
<i>The fans let him know</i> <i>how they feel about it.</i>
"观众对此非常不满"
- Excuse me. - Sure.
- 失陪  - 没事
<i>This could get ugly.</i>
"看来场面就要失控了"
- Rock. - Yo, Paulie.
- 洛奇  - 嘿 保利
They're gonna be talking about that fake Looney Tune fight.
他们马上就要聊那场玩具比赛了
Hey, come on. We're about to serve today's special.
行了  我正要上今天的特色菜呢
Italian food cooked up by a bunch of Mexicans ain't so special.
一堆墨西哥人煮的意大利菜  还能有什么特色？
Hey, yo.
嘿  你啊
Hey, I skipped work for this.
嘿  我逃了工作就为看这个
What an ugly dog.
这只狗可真丑
It's a cute dog.
它很可爱
- Hey, Rock. - Yeah?
- 洛奇  - 什么？
I'm gonna take off. That stuff back there is pretty cool.
我要回去了  墙上那些奖牌很酷
- Oh, you like that? - Yeah, man.
- 你喜欢么？- 当然 朋友
- Thanks, I appreciate it. - I'll catch you later.
- 谢谢 我很高兴  - 下次再见
All right.
好的
- Who's the criminal? - He's a nice kid.
- 那小混混是谁？- 他是个好孩子
He dresses like a bum.
穿得像个小流氓
Coming from a human hamper, that's quite a compliment.
从你嘴里说出来  还真是恭维之辞
Hide the silverware.
把银餐具收起来
That's nice.
没关系
Hey, Spider.
嘿  斯柏德
Didn't you knock out that bum once?
那蠢货被你击倒取胜过吗？
Will you give it a rest?
你一边歇着不行么？
I'm gonna be late for work for this. Give me a break, huh?
我要看完这个再去干活  让我歇会吧？
All right. Just for a few seconds.
好吧  只看一会儿
<i>In the late '60s, a simulated fight</i> <i>took place between two legends...</i>
60 年代末  拳坛传奇默罕默德·阿里
<i>... Muhammad Ali</i> <i>and Rocky Marciano.</i>
和洛奇·马克西亚诺这两位传奇人物之间
<i>Marciano long retired,</i> <i>and Ali unable to fight legitimately...</i>
举行过一场模拟比赛  马克西亚诺早已退休
<i>... for three years for having refused</i> <i>induction into the armed forces...</i>
而因拒服兵役的罪名被罚禁赛三年的阿里
<i>... was in need of money,</i> <i>and agreed to the dream match...</i>
因经济拮据  便同意了这场梦幻之赛
<i>... whose outcome would be</i> <i>decided by a computer.</i>
而结果则由电脑来决定
<i>It's almost 35 years</i> <i>since Rocky Marciano...</i>
35 年前洛奇·马克西亚诺
<i>... won the much-disputed</i> <i>computer decision...</i>
赢得了这场颇具争议的模拟赛
<i>... and guess what?</i> <i>Not much has changed.</i>
而今天呢？并没什么不同
<i>Last week, Rocky Balboa</i> <i>won a decisive fight...</i>
上周洛奇·巴尔博亚获得了一场决定性的胜利
See? That's the cartoon fight I'm telling you about.
快看  这就是我说的那场玩具比赛
Yeah.
是啊
<i>A stunning knockout.</i>
一次令人印象深刻的击倒获胜
<i>Keep in mind, this is taking</i> <i>the human factor out of it.</i>
请大家记住  这场比赛没有人为因素干预
- <i>The computer says Balboa...</i> - Beautiful.
- 电脑认为巴尔博亚…  - 打得漂亮
<i>... would be triumphant, KO 13.</i> <i>And here's some of the fallout:</i>
…将在第 13 回合击倒对手获胜  下面是一些不同意见
<i>What started as a simple</i> <i>form of entertainment...</i>
原本形式简单的娱乐节目
<i>... has become a rallying cry</i> <i>for people who think...</i>
现在却变成了叫阵 观众们
<i>... an old-school athlete like Balboa</i> <i>could actually be better.</i>
认为象巴尔博亚这种老派选手  可以表现得再好一点
<i>Computer technology has to create</i> <i>what isn't. That's just not responsible.</i>
而用电脑科技创造的虚拟世界  就显得不切实际
Get therapy, will you?
去找精神科医生吧
<i>How do you think Balboa</i> <i>would have done against Dixon?</i>
你认为巴尔博亚和迪克逊打胜算如何？
<i>Badly. Personally, I think Balboa</i> <i>was completely overrated.</i>
会很惨  我个人觉得巴尔博亚完全被高估了
<i>He owns a restaurant</i> <i>in South Philly.</i>
他在费城南部开了家小餐馆
<i>What's the specialty,</i> <i>pounded chicken?</i>
招牌菜是什么  打烂的鸡肉？
<i>Anyway, I would have paid to see</i> <i>the fight. Next topic, NAS CAR...</i>
不过我还是愿意出钱去看这比赛  下一个话题
<i>... and the controversy</i> <i>that won't go away.</i>
关于全美赛车协会的争辩还在继续…
<i>Let's go back to Sunday's race...</i>
让我们回到周日的比赛…
Hey, hey, hey, cheer up.
嘿  嘿  嘿  开心点
It's free advertisement. Come on. Meat house calls.
免费广告啊  走了  肉厂来电话了
Yo, Robert.
嘿  罗伯特
What are you doing out so late?
你那么晚了还在外面干吗？
I tried calling, but nothing was picking up.
我打过电话  但是没人接
- Is something wrong? - I just wanted to come by...
- 有什么事吗？- 我只是想过来…
...and see you in person. - Wanna come inside?
- …看看你  - 想进来坐一会吗？
No. I just wanna get your opinion on something.
不了  我只是想问下你对一些事的看法
Sure. Opinion on what?
好的  什么方面的看法？
You know, they say you only go around once, right?
你听说过 "人生不能重来" 吗  对吧？
- Yeah, I've heard that. - Well...
- 对 我听过  - 好的…
...I think I wanna, like, do something.
…我觉得我该做点什么  比如…
- Like what? - Fight.
- 比如什么？- 拳击
You know, nothing big. Small stuff, like locally. You know.
不是大型的  是小规模的  比如地区比赛
Don't you think you're too, you know, old?
你不觉得你太… 太老了么？
You think you ought to stop trying things...
也是啊  可是…
...because you had a few too many birthdays? I do not.
多过了几次生日就什么都不能做了吗？我不觉得
People will think you're crazy.
人们会觉得你疯了
What's crazy about standing toe to toe saying, "I am," you know?
理直气壮地对人说  "就是我"  有什么可疯的？
That's just ego talking.
那样说太自大了
What are you trying to prove to other people, Pop?
你想向大家证明什么呢  爸爸？
Prove? Listen, I stopped thinking...
证明？听着  我…
...the way other people think a long time ago.
很早以前我就不在乎别人是怎么想的了
You gotta think like you think.
你得有自己的想法
- I do. - Do you? Good.
- 我有  - 你有？很好
You gotta face reality, okay? It's a different world now.
可你得面对现实  现在和过去不一样了
Only the clothes is different.
只是穿着不太一样
I really don't know what you want from me.
我真不知道  你要从我这得到什么看法
I just wanted us to get involved. You know, like, home team.
只是希望我们能和睦相处  家族队
Look, whatever it is, whatever you're going through, it'll pass.
听着  无论你过去经历过什么  那终究是过去
Yeah, you're probably right.
是啊  或许你是对的
Time is gonna catch up to all of us.
我们最终都会变老的
- Especially if you're standing still. - Hey, come on.
- 尤其在你停滞不前的时候  - 嘿 别这样
Look, I'm gonna call you in the morning.
我明天上午再给你打电话
- <i>Did you tell this to your kid?</i> - <i>Yeah, I did.</i>
- 你把这事告诉你儿子了？- 是的 说了
- <i>What'd he think, you're nuts, right?</i> - <i>Yeah.</i>
- 他是不是觉得你疯了？- 差不多
Oh, well, he don't believe in you? Welcome to my world, buddy.
看吧  他不相信你？欢迎来我的世界  伙伴
Rocko, nobody's giving you no title shot.
洛奇  没有人会给你拳王头衔
I know that. I don't want one.
我知道  我也不需要
So this isn't a mental disturbance?
那么是不是精神上受了什么打击？
No.
不是
You're mad because they took down your statue?
你是气他们拆了你的雕像？
Not really, no.
真的不是
If it's about money, just hang a sign around your neck saying, "Punch me."
如果是因为钱的原因  那么你只要在胸前挂块牌子
Five dollars, you'll make big money.
"五美圆打一拳"  那么你就可以发财了
What? You haven't peaked yet?
怎么？你还没有登上过拳坛顶峰？
- Peaked? - Yeah, peaked.
- 顶峰？- 是的 顶峰
I don't know. There's still some stuff in the basement.
我不知道  总觉得有些事积压在心里
- What basement? - In here.
- 哪里？- 这里 心底
Tell me about the stuff.
告诉我吧
- What about it? - Tell me about the stuff inside.
- 关于什么？- 说说你心底的事吧
- Is it angry? - Angry?
- 是愤怒么？- 愤怒？
Are you mad because Adrian left you?
你是不是  因为艾黛丽安的离开而发疯了？
She didn't leave, Paulie. She died.
她没有离开我  保利  她去世了
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
好  好  好  好
You know, sometimes it's hard to breathe.
你知道么  有时我觉得呼吸都困难
You know, I feel, like, this beast inside me.
你知道么  我感觉就像有野兽在我身体里
It's okay, Rocko. Please, it's okay.
会没事的  洛奇  会没事的
Is it okay?
会没事么？
I just never knew it was supposed to be this hard.
我甚至从来不知道它会如此的猛烈
It wasn't supposed to be like this, Paulie. You know, it...
本不应该这样的  保利  你明白的…
So you wanna come by and help me train?
那么你能过来  协助我训练么？
I got a job here.
我这里有工作
I understand.
我明白
Remember you said if you stay one place long enough...
记得你说过 "如果你在一个地方呆久了…
...you become that place?
…你就会对那地方有感情了"
Rocko, this is all I got.
洛奇  这就是我现在的全部
I understand, Paulie. I do.
我理解  保利  真的
If you get time and come down and see me train, I'd appreciate it.
如果你有时间来看我训练的话  我会很感激
Of course, Rocko.
当然  洛奇
Bye, Paulie.
再见  保利
Goodbye, Rocko.
再见  洛奇
Take care, Rocko.
你多保重
<i>This plenary session of the</i> <i>Pennsylvania Athletic Commission...</i>
现在召开宾夕法尼亚州运动委员会全体会议…
...is convened in order to consider the application of Rocky Balboa...
洛奇·巴尔博亚先生申请获得自由职业拳师执照
...for the issuance of a discretionary professional boxing license...
由于其无被许可权  本委员会遂决定…
...due to his ineligibility to be licensed as a matter of right.
召开全体会议  以决定是否为其颁发执照
Mr. Balboa, you're welcome here. Since you're representing yourself...
欢迎参加本次会议  鉴于您是代表自己…
...we invite you to make an opening statement, if you'd like to.
我们请您作一个开场陈述  如果您想的话
No, I was just curious how I did, that's all.
不用  我只对结果感兴趣  没别的
All right, well, the Medical Advisory Board has informed us...
那好吧  医学顾问团委员会已告知我们…
...that the battery of tests to which you've been subjected...
您之前所接受的一系列医学检查…
...you've passed these tests with flying colors.
已经全部顺利通过了
And we congratulate you for that.
我们为此祝贺您
- Thanks. - However, this commission...
- 谢谢  - 然而 本委员会…
...in good conscience, cannot recommend you for a license...
出于公平考虑  不能为您颁发这个执照
...and we therefore deny your application.
因此决定拒绝您的申请
- Didn't I do what you asked? - Yes, you did.
- 我没照要求做吗？- 当然不是
So I should get a license, right?
那就该给我执照
Not exactly.
不完全是
So why did you give me all them tests if you was never passing me?
那为什么还要让我做那些测试呢？
We've gotta stand by our decision here...
我们必须坚持这个决定…
...and we have to deny your request for a license at this time.
这次我们只能拒绝您的执照申请
Yo, don't I got some rights?
我应该有权利吧？
What rights do you think you're referring to?
您指的权利是什么权利？
Like in that official paper they wrote down the street?
就像街上那些官方告示里说的权利
- That's the Bill of Rights. - Bill of Rights.
- 那是人权法案  - 没错 人权法案
Don't it say something about going after what makes you happy?
它不是说要找让人开心的东西吗？
No, that's "the pursuit of happiness." But what's your point?
不  那是指"追求幸福"  你到底想说什么？
My point is I'm pursuing something, and nobody looks too happy about it.
我要说我想追求幸福  但没人因此而开心
But we're just looking out for your interests.
但我们是为你的利益考虑
I appreciate that, but maybe you're looking out for your interests more.
我很感激  但也许你更在乎的是你们自己的利益
You shouldn't ask people to come here and pay the freight on something.
如果申请人不够资格  你就不该让他花钱过来
They pay, it still ain't good enough. You think that's right?
钱花了  他还是不够资格  你觉得这样对么？
Maybe you're doing your job, but why you gotta stop me from doing mine?
也许你是在尽你的职责  但你为什么非要阻止我呢？
If you're willing to go through all the battling to get where you want to get...
如果你愿意通过一切障碍去达到你的目的地…
...who's got the right to stop you?
谁有权利阻止你呢？
Maybe you got something you never finished, something you wanna do.
也许你也有没完成的事  很想做的事
Something you never said to somebody, something!
或者从没告诉过别人的事  无论什么！
And you're told no, even after you pay your dues.
可就算付过费  别人却说 "不行"
Who's got the right to tell you that? Who? Nobody!
谁有权这样对你说？谁？没人可以！
It's your right to listen to your gut. It's nobody's right to say no...
坚持这个决定是你的权利  但当你赢得了…
...after you earn the right to be what you wanna be or do what you wanna do!
实现梦想的权利时  没人有权对你说不！
The older I get, the more things I gotta leave behind. That's life.
人越老  该抛弃的东西就越多  这就是生活
The only thing I'm asking you guys to leave on the table is what's right.
我只希望你们能给正确的事情留点余地
Yo! Have you seen the paper today?
嘿！看今天的报纸了么？
Front row. Front row.
头条新闻！头条新闻！
That is so great.
那真是太棒了
- All right, all right. - Let's go get some food. Food.
- 好吧 好吧  - 我们去吃点东西
- Let's get a beer. Come on. - Come on.
- 喝杯酒去 走啦  - 来啊
The last two pay-per-views were in the toilet.
近两期付费平台的拳赛几乎无人问津
You're not making heavyweight-championship money.
重量级拳王锦标赛赚不到钱了
There's a bunch of nobodies out there, Mase.
外面都是些无名小卒  梅森
I wanna talk to you about an opportunity we should run with.
我想和你谈谈  关于一个赚钱的好机会
Look at me. You heard Rocky Balboa applied for a license and got one?
看着我
- I heard. Forget about him. - Hear me out.
- 我知道 不值一提  - 听我说完
You want me to fight a guy I can beat with both hands tied behind my back.
你要我和这个双手背着都能打赢的家伙比赛么？
Everybody knows you could beat him sitting down. That's not what it's about.
大家都知道你坐着也能打赢  但这不是比赛的重点
It's about making money. We gotta capitalize on that computer fight.
重点是赚钱  我们要投资电脑拳击赛
This could do a million buys. That's 15, 20 million to you.
这场比赛可以卖出百万张票  你能赚到一、两千万呢
- Forget it. - No one's beating the door down...
- 算了吧  - 现在已经没有人敲门…
...to watch you fight anymore. - We got guaranteed fights.
- 来看你比赛了  - 不让我们办一场包赢的比赛
You wanna do this now in front of your friends, we'll do it now.
如果你现在做的话  你就会马上在你朋友面前泄漏秘密
We got nothing. All the pay-per-view fights you come up with got rejected.
那我们就一无所有了  所有的付费频道都拒绝了你
You know why? They're all bums out there. Nobody cares about them.
知道为什么吗？你的对手太弱  比赛不够刺激
There's no marquee value. But this Balboa thing is interesting.
已经没有看点了  但是这个巴尔博亚很有趣
- I don't wanna do it. - Listen to me.
- 我不想和他打  - 听我说
It's a has-been, never-gonna-be world. Call it nostalgia, whatever you want...
他曾经盛极一时  但是现在时代不同了
...but people relate to that stuff. This is a no-lose. It's all good.
只要能引起观众的共鸣  这是比只赚不亏的买卖
- Good for who? - For you! Not for me! For you!
- 而且有好处- 对谁有好处？
Maybe you don't understand. People don't like you no more.
也许你还不明白  人们已经不再喜欢你了
They don't follow you. They're not supporting you anymore. Understand?
他们不再追随你  不再支持你  明白么？
Don't look at me like I'm messing with your legacy.
别那样看着我  好像我在搞砸你的比赛信条
Every jock now thinks they got a legacy.
每个运动员都认为他们拥有一个信条
A legacy is what you get instead of getting paid. That's a legacy.
信条是你付钱也买不到的  那才是一个信条
- Don't talk to me like I'm stupid. - I'm not no more.
- 别当我傻瓜  - 我没有
Everybody knows you could kick this old man's ass. But you don't.
每个人都知道你可以把这个老东西打翻  但是你不能
Leave him with a little dignity, so they say:
留给他一些自尊  然后别人就会说
"Mason Dixon's got compassion. He's a decent guy, he's a nice guy."
"梅森·迪克逊有同情心  他是个好人  是个正派的人"
You get a whole new audience, we'll double your money.
你得个满堂彩  以后出场费就可以翻倍了
You want a new image? That's how you get it.
你想换个新形象吗？这就是机会
To replace the one that you two made?
换掉你们两个设计的形象？
Whoa, wait. We made your world green. You made the rest.
等等  我们让你铺平道路  你做剩下的事就行
This is you. You made all this junk happen.
这才是你  你让所有这些蠢事发生
I've had it up to here with this mess.
我已经把这里变得一团糟了
Time for me to make changes. I'm going to Martin's gym.
是时候让我做些改变了  我要去马丁的拳馆
- We'll talk about it. - Forget this crap.
- 我们再谈谈这个事  - 忘了这个蠢事吧
I want Martin back. There's nothing to talk about.
我要马丁回来  不然什么都免谈
- How you doing? - Hey, what a surprise.
- 你好吗？- 嘿 真是稀客啊
I was driving around the neighborhood, I thought...
我正好开车路过这里  于是我想…
...why not drive by and say hello? - You wanna come inside?
- 为什么不过来打个招呼呢？- 进来坐一会吗？
No, the dog needs some exercise. You wanna take a little walk?
不了  这狗需要运动  你想一起散步么？
- Yeah, yeah. All right. - It's nice outside.
- 好 好 当然  - 外面天气很好
- All right. - Nice and brisk.
- 是的  - 凉爽宜人
When did you get a dog?
什么时候养狗了？
We picked up Punchy a couple of days back.
我们几天前领养的 "拳头"
- Punchy? - Yeah.
- "拳头"？- 是啊
You named your dog Punchy?
你给你的狗取名叫 "拳头"？
Your kid come up with the name.
事实上名字是你儿子取的
Oh, yeah? I think that's disrespectful.
哦  是吗？这个名字很没礼貌
Oh, no, no. It's fine, really.
不  不会  真的  挺好
No, it's easy to remember and it's all that, you know.
很不错  很好记  你不觉得？
Listen, what do you think about coming over to the restaurant?
那么  你觉得到我的餐厅来怎么样呢？
- What for? - Well, you know, for, like...
- 来干吗？- 当然是过来…
For work. The hostess is gonna be having a kid. You'd do good.
上班了  女领班快要生孩子了  你来顶替她不错
- I don't know. - I'm telling you, you'd do so good.
- 我不知道  - 我告诉你 你能做得很好
I appreciate what you're doing for my kid, but I can't.
我很感激你为我孩子所做的  但是我不能
Hey, listen, I think you'd like it a lot.
嘿  听着  我认为你会很喜欢的
It's a nice environment, it's very pleasant.
不错的环境  非常舒服
Yeah, can we drop it?
是啊  我们能不能不谈这个？
What's bothering you?
你有什么担心的？
Nothing. It's all right. Listen, I gotta get back.
没什么  很好  听着  我要回去了
- No, it ain't all right. - Oh, come on.
- 不 不好  - 哦 得了
- What? - I'm gonna be the first person...
- 怎么了？- 你想客人进来时…
...people see when they walk in? - You give out menus.
- 看到的第一个人就是我？- 你只要分发菜单
You say, "Hello, how are you?" You sit people down.
说声 "你好"  带个位子就行了
Look, if I can do it, anybody can do it.
听着  我能做的事  任何人都能做的
You could find 10 better people, a hundred better people for this job.
你能找到上百个比我更胜任这工作的人
Give it a try, like two weeks.
试试看嘛  就两个礼拜
I don't wanna try.
我不想试
- Who put this stuff in your head? - Nobody.
- 是谁给你洗脑了？- 没有
Well, it just don't get in there by itself.
那你不会自己产生这种想法
Thanks for coming by.
谢谢你过来看我
Yo, when was the last time you went dancing? Has it been a while?
嘿  你上次跳舞是什么时候？很久了吧？
- Why are you asking? - I'm asking because...
- 为什么这么问？- 我问是因为…
...you dance around these problems, you might as well dance with me.
你一直绕开这些问题"起舞"  你不妨和我跳一跳
I ain't that good, but I'm better than the average bear.
我不是跳得很好  但比一般的大块头要好很多
Where that came from, I don't know.
我也不知道这是为什么
- You're crazy. - A little bit.
- 你疯了  - 有点
But the way you're thinking and talking, it's a little crazy too.
但是你思考和说话的方式  同样也有点疯
Come on, you deserve better. Really. Come on over.
来吧  别太委屈自己了  真的  过来帮我
I need you to class my place up. Philly needs you.
来给我的餐厅加点颜色  费城需要你
And if you say, "Screw you, creepo" again, I totally understand.
如果你再说 "去你的  小人"  那我也能理解
But I'm warning you, I'm gonna put myself...
但是我警告你  我会立刻毫不犹豫地站到马路中间
...and stand here, me and Punchy, and wave to the first bus, say:
然后带着 "拳头" 站到那里  看到公车就招手  并且说
"Come on over here and mash me!
"开过来碾死我吧"！
Little Marie turned down the job at the restaurant.
"因为小玛丽不答应来我餐厅上班"
She thinks she's better than us."
"我想她是看不起我们"
Oh, yeah? Well, there hasn't been a bus down here in 20 years.
哦  是吗？其实这里已经有二十多年没有公车经过了
- Yeah? - No.
- 真的？- 对
That was a close call.
真的是好险
Listen, seriously. Come on over. It'd be nice.
好了  说真的  来上班  包你满意
All right.
好吧
Paulie!
保利！
Sorry, Paulie.
不好意思  保利
Sorry.
不好意思
How are you? Get my unusual up there.
你好吗？把我这个不寻常的东西放那里
Excuse me. Deliveries are in the back.
不好意思  送货的在后面
I'm not a delivery guy.
我不是送货的
Well, do you have a reservation?
那你有预定吗？
Do I look like a freaking Indian?
难道我看上去象印第安人吗？
Hey, Rock? Rocky?
嘿  洛奇  洛奇
I think we've got a little bit of a problem with this guy.
我认为这家伙有点麻烦
Problem? No, no, he's just a relative.
麻烦？不  不会  他是我亲戚
Oh, okay.
哦  好吧
Yo, Paulie.
嘿  保利
- What happened to your eye? - I hit it.
- 你的眼睛怎么了？- 我自己打的
- Why? - Needed to.
- 为什么？- 因为有必要
What happened?
发生什么事了？
- I'm celebrating, Rock. - Why?
- 我在庆祝 洛奇  - 庆祝什么？
- I retired. - Retired?
- 我退休了  - 退休？
So when did they start giving retired people meat...
他们什么时候把退休时发的礼物…
...instead of watches, Paulie?
…手表换成猪肉了  保利？
I don't need a watch.
我不需要手表
I got a watch! You gave me a watch!
我有手表！你给我的表！
Paulie...
保利
I don't need no goddamn watch.
我才不要什么破手表呢
- Yo, Paulie. - I got a watch!
- 保利  - 我有手表！
I got two watches!
我有两块手表！
Yo, Paulie!
嘿  保利！
Yo, Paulie.
嘿  保利
Rock.
洛奇
It takes guts climbing back in that ring, knowing you're gonna take a beating.
再上擂台需要很大勇气  因为你知道会挨打
You're gonna do all right, Rocko.
但你会没事的  洛奇
How do you know that?
你怎么知道？
The stuff in the basement.
因为你心里有勇气
Thanks, Paulie.
谢谢  保利
- Hey. - Hey, Rock, how are you?
- 嘿  - 嘿 洛奇 你好吗？
- You okay? - Yeah, good. How are you?
- 还好吗？- 是的 很好 你怎么样？
- Yeah, fine. This is great. - Good.
- 很好 好极了  - 好的
Listen, some guys over there wanna talk to you.
对了  那边的那些人想跟你谈谈
- Okay. You got it. - Okay?
- 好的 我过去  - 好
- Thanks for coming by. I appreciate it. - Our pleasure.
- 多谢惠顾 非常地感谢  - 很荣幸
- Wanna hear stories? - What kind of stories?
- 想听故事吗？- 什么故事？
Well, a lot of people like to hear these old fight stories.
很多人喜欢听我讲过去比赛的故事
- Maybe later. - Okay.
- 也许等会儿吧  - 好的
I'm Lou DiBella. This is L.C. Luco. He's Mason Dixon's manager.
我是鲁·迪贝拉  这位是卢克  梅森·迪克逊的经纪人
- Will you sit down and join us? - Sure.
- 你能坐下和我们谈谈吗？- 当然
You know, we have the promotional contract for Mason Dixon...
你知道  我们和梅森·迪克逊有宣传合约
...who's a big fan. - Really?
- 对了 你还是他的偶像  - 真的？
When he heard you were interested in fighting...
当他听说你想复出时…
...he thought why not try to work something out?
他就想出了一个好点子
Like a special event. Like a first-class exhibition fight.
一场特殊的盛会  一场顶级的表演赛
- Why me? - He respects the hell out of you.
- 为什么找我？- 他非常尊敬你
All right? And let's be honest, that computer fight got people curious.
知道吗？我们很有诚意  电脑拳赛引起观众的好奇
- This could be very interesting. - I ain't interested...
- 这可能会很有趣  - 我没有兴趣…
...in getting, like, mangled and embarrassed.
被人家糟蹋和自取其辱
No, that's not gonna happen. Never happen.
不  这个情况不会发生  绝对不会
Truthfully, I was thinking more on a, like...
坦白说  我更想要的一个…
...miniscule, small level. You know. Small fights, not big fights.
…小规模的拳击赛  不要盛大比赛  小规模的
Small fights. Things that... Local. You know what I mean?
地方性的  小一点的就行  L. C 你明白我的意思吗？
Not a bad idea. Don't think of it as big. Think of it like an exhibition.
构想不错  不要把它想成是大赛  就把它当成表演赛好了
Think of it as a glorified sparring session. Here's something you'll like.
美其名曰是一场拳击示范赛  但细节你会喜欢
We're gonna donate a portion of the gate to charity.
我们会捐出部分收入给慈善机构
- That's always nice. - It's good to give.
- 这是件好事  - 乐善好施
Yeah.
是啊
Where's it taking place?
在哪里比？
- Las Vegas. - Las Vegas.
- 拉斯维加斯  - 拉斯维加斯
Nice and warm. This cold's gotta be killing you.
温暖舒适  这儿都快冻死人了
- Little stiff. - You move better when you're warmer.
- 快冻僵了  - 暖和一点 步伐会更好
- Yeah. - And if nothing else...
- 是啊  - 如果没有其他问题的话…
...you'll have new stories to tell.
…你马上可以有新的故事讲了
- I really gotta think about this. - Absolutely.
- 你让我好好想想  - 当然
- Is that okay? - I understand. No problem.
- 可以吗？- 我理解 没问题
I'm gonna go over there. You can order something.
我要去那边了  你们可以点些东西吃
- What do you recommend? - It's all edible.
- 你推荐什么好吃的？- 都是好东西
Okay. Thanks.
好的  谢谢
We got him. Imagine if Dixon met this bastard in his prime?
他心动了  如果迪克逊遇上这个老头鼎盛时期
- He'd kill him. Kill him. - You ain't kidding.
- 他会杀了他的  - 你说的没错
Man, I'm confused.
我真有点疑惑
I didn't think this was gonna come along.
我从没想过这会真的发生
But this is what you wanted, right?
但这就是你想要的  对吗？
I don't know. You know, I talk and I talk.
我不清楚  你知道  我只是一直说一直说
Sometimes I think what I'm saying is true...
有时候我觉得我说的都是真的
...and then I look at myself and I'm not even sure what is true anymore.
然后我看看自己  连自己都不知道什么才是真的
Because it's like, I pushed this crazy idea about fighting.
就因为这样  我才有了再比赛的疯狂想法
I mean, what's it all about?
我意思是  这都是为什么呢？
Do I really care about standing toe to toe and all that stuff...
难道我真的在乎面对面的比赛  或是其他什么…
...or, like my kid says, is it just, like, ego?
…也许就像我儿子说的  是我盲目自大？
Or am I this old pug who's just trying to replace old pain with new pain?
还是我这把老骨头想用新伤代替旧伤？
I don't know. I don't know.
我不知道  我不知道
Look, I know I usually don't say a lot.
听着  我懂  我通常不怎么说话
I'm always listening and looking.
我总是更愿意倾听和观察
But who you are, the part of you that's so full of life...
但那个最真实的你  其实一直充满着生命的活力
...we all have that feeling, that fire...
我们都有这种感觉  这种激情
...but usually never get a chance to use it. And then it just goes away.
但不是都有机会来释放的  然后激情就会慢慢消失
But you can. You've got this opportunity, so do it. Why not?
但你可以  你有机会  去吧  为什么不呢？
I mean, this is who you are. This is who you'll always be.
我意思是  这才是你  这才是真正的你
And you don't move aside for nobody until you're ready to move.
你从不听任何人使唤  总是坚持自己的路
And it doesn't matter how this looks to other people.
别人怎么看没关系
All that matters is how it looks to you.
重要的是你怎么看
Rocky.
洛奇
Rocky, look at me.
洛奇  看着我
How it looks to you.
重要的是你怎么看
And if this is something that you wanna do...
如果这是你想做的事
...and if this is something that you gotta do, then you do it.
如果这是你非做不可的事  那么就去做吧
Fighters fight.
背水一战
You're not gonna punch me, are you?
你不会对我出拳吧？
Listen, I gotta go before I wear out my welcome. I'll see you tomorrow.
在你开始讨厌我前我必须要走了  明天见
Thanks.
谢谢
Fighters fight, right?
拳手就该打拳  对吗？
It's rare when you get to promote an event bigger than boxing. This is.
很少有比推广拳击赛更大的活动了  这次就是
Skill versus will, with part of the proceeds going to charity.
是技巧与意志的对垒  部分所得将捐给慈善机构
The brainchild of Mason Dixon, to honor past heavyweight champions.
这是梅森·迪克逊的创意  以此向昔日重量级拳王
Warriors like Rocky Balboa. Let's open it up for questions.
洛奇·巴尔博亚这样的勇士致敬  现在可以提问了
Hey, champ!
嘿  洛奇！
A few great fighters have fought in their 50s, often with disastrous results.
很少有拳手年逾五十还能打赢拳赛  通常都会惨败
Why risk the danger and embarrassment?
为什么还要冒这个风险  弄得自己难堪？
The smart money says you have virtually no chance.
圈内人士说  你根本没有机会
A puncher always has a chance. This fight will be competitive.
任何拳手都有机会  这场比赛一定会有看头
Why are you doing this, Rocky?
你为什么要这么做  洛奇？
<i>I don't know, I'd rather do</i> <i>something I love badly than...</i>
不知道  我宁可做自己热爱的事…
<i>Than to feel bad by not</i> <i>doing something you love.</i>
也不想因为不做而抱憾终生
Rocky, the press has labeled you a Balboasaurus.
洛奇  媒体把你称作已经发酵的巴尔博亚
How do you feel about that?
你对此什么感觉？
Let's say the following happens: You win, we'll say you beat an old guy.
梅森  如果你胜利了  我们会说你打败了一个老头
You lose, say a thumb in the eye, you'll be the joke of the decade.
你输了  哪怕失之毫厘  都会沦为笑柄
You all know that will never happen. This is only an exhibition.
你们都知道这不可能发生  这只是场表演赛
Don't go trying to make more out of this than that computer tried.
不要以为这比电脑拳赛特别很多
Isn't this sport in enough trouble without these circus events?
体坛问题这么多  为什么还要搞这种马戏比赛？
- Next question. - On the surface, this looks like...
- 下一个问题  - 表面上
...a cheap bit of ring theater between, no offense...
这场比赛就像一场廉价的闹剧  无意冒犯…
...a has-been and a man whose own credible legacy...
一方是昔日的传奇拳王
...and popularity is in doubt.
另一方的传统和声誉正受到怀疑
- What's the upside? - Doubt?
- 有什么好处呢？- 怀疑？
Upside? I mean...
好处？我意思是…
What do you mean, upside? I mean, what do I have to do?
你说的好处指什么？还要我怎样？
You know, I'm 33-0 with 30 knockouts.
我 33 胜 0 负  30场击倒
I'm doing you people a favor. I'm having this exhibition for you.
我在帮你们  我为你们才参加表演赛
You gonna get up here and make a mockery out of me? I'm the champ.
你们却站在这里嘲笑我？我是拳王
I mean, I get pissed, this guy get hurt.
惹我生气  他会受伤
See you at the fight.
赛场上见
The guy's a joke. He's gonna get crushed.
他是个笑话  会死的很惨
- Look who's here. - How you doing?
- 看 这是谁？- 你好吗？
- Have you seen my father? - He's in the back.
- 你看到我爸爸了吗？- 他在后面
This place has never served this many meals. It's unbelievable.
这地方生意从来没这么好过  难以置信
You're doing good? Hope you're enjoying everything, all right?
吃的好吗？希望用餐愉快
Excuse me.
失陪
How you doing? Glad you come by.
你怎么来了？很高兴看到你
Can I talk with you?
能跟你谈谈吗？
- Sure. - Can we do it outside?
- 当然  - 能外面谈吗？
- So you're going through with this? - I start training tomorrow.
- 你打算进行下去？- 我明天开始训练
Hey, Rock. I made some connections.
嘿  洛奇  我联系了几个人
I can make some money on this, endorsements.
我可以靠赞助商赚几个小钱
Absolutely. Do that.
当然  去做吧
- Thank you, Rock. Okay. - Sure.
- 谢谢 洛奇 好的  - 没事
- So you nervous about the fight? - Scared to death.
- 你对比赛紧张吗？- 怕得要命
- You don't look scared. - Well, I ain't supposed to.
- 你看上去一点不怕  - 是啊 我没什么好怕的
Then you don't have to do it.
其实你没必要去比赛的
Yeah, well, I think I do.
是啊  但我认为我应该去
You know, living with you, it hasn't been easy.
你知道  和你生活向来不容易
People see me but they think of you.
人们看着我  想到的却是你
Now with all this going on, it's gonna be worse than ever.
现在发生的这些事  只能让这一切更糟
- It don't have to be. - Sure it does!
- 不会那样的  - 当然会！
- Why? You've got a lot going on, kid. - What, my last name?
- 为什么？你过得很好啊 孩子  - 因为我的姓？
That's the reason I got a decent job.
我才能得到一份体面的工作
That's why people deal with me in the first place.
这也是为什么别人总会优先考虑我的原因
Now I start to get a little ahead...
我终于要做出些名堂了…
...I start to get a little something for myself, and this happens.
为我自己做出些成绩  却出了这事
Now, I'm asking you as a favor not to go through with this.
爸爸  算我求你帮个忙  不要再进行下去了
This is gonna end up bad for you, and it's gonna end up bad for me.
事情的结局对你我来说都不是一件好事
- You think I'm hurting you? - Yeah. In a way, you are.
- 我伤害你了？- 对 某种意义上 是
That's the last thing I ever wanted to do.
我最不想伤害的就是你
I know that's not what you wanna do, but that's just the way that it is.
我知道你不想伤害我  但是事情就是这样
Don't you care what people think? Doesn't it bother you that people...
你不在乎别人怎么想吗？别人要把你…
...are making you out to be a joke and that I'll be included in that?
…当笑话  而我也不幸成了这笑话的一部分？
Do you think that's right? Do you?
你觉得这样对吗？对吗？
You ain't gonna believe this, but you used to fit right here.
你可能不相信  我常这样托着你
I'd hold you up and say to your mother:
把你举起来  对你母亲说
"This kid is gonna be the best kid in the world.
"这孩子会成为世界上最棒的小孩"
This kid is gonna be somebody better than anybody ever knew."
"会比我认识的所有人都要棒"
And you grew up good and wonderful.
你茁壮地长大成人了
It was great just watching, every day was like a privilege.
看你成长的每一天都是一种恩惠
Then the time come for you to be your own man and take on the world...
然后就是你自己奋斗的人生了  可以自己承担一切
...and you did. But somewhere along the line, you changed.
但不知从什么时候开始  你变了
You stopped being you.
你不再做自己了
You let people stick a finger in your face and tell you you're no good.
让别人对你指手划脚  说你不好
And when things got hard, you started looking for something to blame...
而且当遇上不顺心的事时  你开始怪罪于其他事物
...like a big shadow.
比如说巨大的阴影
Let me tell you something you already know.
我告诉你几句老生常谈吧
The world ain't all sunshine and rainbows.
世界不是充满阳光和彩虹
It's a very mean and nasty place, and I don't care how tough you are...
而是非常卑鄙肮脏  不管你有多强大…
...it will beat you to your knees and keep you there if you let it.
如果不够坚定  你就会被打倒  永远都不能翻身
You, me or nobody is gonna hit as hard as life.
无论是你还是我  没人比生活更强大
But it ain't about how hard you hit. It's about how hard you can get hit...
但这不是强大不强大的问题  而是受到打击之后…
...and keep moving forward.
能否继续向前
How much you can take and keep moving forward.
能承受巨大的打击  还能勇往直前
That's how winning is done!
这才是真正的胜利！
If you know what you're worth, go and get what you're worth.
如果知道自己的价值  就去拿你应得的
But you gotta be willing to take the hits, and not pointing fingers...
但是要勇于承受打击  而不是指责别人…
...saying you ain't where you wanna be because of him or her or anybody!
说是因为这个人或那个人  你才没实现梦想！
Cowards do that, and that ain't you! You're better than that!
懦夫才那样  你不是懦夫！你非常出色！
I'm always gonna love you no matter what.
无论怎样  我都会爱你
No matter what happens.
无论发生什么  我都爱你
You're my son and you're my blood.
你是我的骨肉  你是我的儿子
You're the best thing in my life.
我一生中最好的礼物
But until you start believing in yourself, you ain't gonna have a life.
你一定要相信自己  才能有真正的人生
Don't forget to visit your mother.
别忘了去看你妈妈
- Yeah, those are beautiful. - Yeah.
- 花很漂亮  - 对
- You get off early from work? - No.
- 你提早下班了？- 没有
I left.
我离开了
I quit.
辞职了
Quit, why?
为什么辞职？
I wasn't very...
我不是很…
I don't know, I just... I didn't fit in there.
我不知道  就是… 就是觉得不适合
I understand.
我理解
- So, what are you gonna do? - Right now?
- 那你打算干吗？- 现在？
Right now I'd rather be with you.
想和你呆在一起
Is that all right?
可以吗？
Yeah.
当然
It's been a long time since I seen a fight.
我好久没看拳赛了
You know all there is to know about fighting...
你了解关于拳击的一切
...so there's no sense us going down that same old road again.
所以咱们没有必要再重复了
To beat this guy, you need speed. You don't have it.
想击败他  你需要速度  而你却没有
And your knees can't take the pounding, so hard running is out.
你的膝盖不能受重击  所以不能跑太快
And you got arthritis in your neck. And you've got calcium deposits...
你的脖子有关节炎  大部分关节还有骨质增生
...on most of your joints, so sparring is out.
所以快速轻拳也不行
I had that problem.
我也有骨质增生
So what we'll be calling on is good old-fashioned blunt-force trauma.
所以我们必须利用传统的强攻和钝拳
Horsepower. Heavy-duty, cast-iron, pile-driving punches...
加大马力  重拳出击  铸铁般强硬  大力出拳
...that will have to hurt so much they'll rattle his ancestors.
要让他疼得要命  打得他跪地求饶才行
Every time you hit him with a shot...
每次你击打他
...it's gotta feel like he tried kissing the express train.
他就是感觉象在亲吻特快列车
Yeah! Let's start building some hurting bombs.
好！让我们来制造些重磅炸弹吧
- Yeah, you'll get it. - You can do it, Rocko!
- 你可以  - 你能行 洛奇！
Getting stronger!
变得更强壮！
- Up! Up! Up! - Come on!
- 用力！用力！用力！- 加油！
Go!
加油！
- Yeah! - Yeah! Yeah!
- 好！- 好！好！
Come on, Rocko!
加油  洛奇！
Come on. Come on. Let's hit them. Hit them.
加油  加油  打它们  打它们
You can do it, Rock.
你能行  洛奇
Getting stronger!
变得更强壮！
- Up, up, up! - Go! Go!
- 用力！用力！用力！- 加油！加油！
All right!
好极了！
Yeah! Yeah!
好！好！
Yeah!
耶！
Rocky Balboa, 217!
洛奇·巴尔博亚  217磅！
The undisputed heavyweight champion, Mason Dixon, 221!
毫无争议的重量级拳王  梅森·迪克逊  221磅！
Thank you very much. I appreciate it, champ. Thanks a lot.
非常感谢  我很感激  拳王  谢谢
<i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i>
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
- Know how much money is in this? - A lot of it.
- 知道这里蕴含着多少钱吗？- 很多
Imagine trying to clean this place.
想象一下清空这个地方
- No, seriously. - Balboa!
- 不 我是认真的  - 巴尔博亚！
You guys, I'll catch up with you all later, okay?
你们先走  我等会儿来找你们
Robert, why don't you hang with me?
罗伯特  你跟我一起吧？
- How you doing, champ? - I'm good.
- 你好吗？拳王  - 很好
No reason for neither one of us to get hurt in this fight.
我们两个都没必要在这场比赛中受伤
I'll do my best to carry you, make sure you save face.
我会尽量照顾好你  保证不让你丢脸
There'd be no embarrassment.
不会让你难堪的
But I promise you, you try to press me, you hit me, you hurt me...
但是我保证  如果你跟来真的  你重击我  弄疼我
...you hit me low, cheap-shot me, I'll get you out of there.
打我腰带以下或是暗算我  我肯定把你打翻
You know, a lot of people come to Vegas to lose. I didn't.
很多人来拉斯维加斯都是失败告终  我不是
It's already over.
已成定局了
Ain't nothing over till it's over.
谁笑到最后还不一定呢
What's that from, the '80s?
这是 80 年代的话吗？
That's probably the '70s.
也可能是 70 年代
Just remember what I said.
记住我说的
Hey, yo, champ.
嘿  冠军
Yo, ain't you a little scared?
你一点也不害怕？
I don't get scared.
我不会害怕
I think you try a little harder when you're scared.
我觉得害怕的时候  人会更努力一些
This is what has worked for me.
起码我是这样  很奏效
- I ain't scared. - Oh, yeah. You ain't scared of me?
- 我不怕  - 哦 是啊 你不怕我？
Come on, let's see what you got. Come on.
快点  给我露两手  快点
Hey, don't hit me, I'm brittle.
嘿  不要击打我  现在我很脆弱
- Hey. - Hi.
- 嘿  - 嗨
- How you doing? - I was just thinking.
- 你还好吗？- 我在想事
- Did you wanna come in? - No, no, no, it's okay.
- 你要进来吗？- 不了 不了 这样可以
I just wanted to...
我只是想要…
...I don' t know, come by and wish you good luck for tomorrow.
说不清楚  只是想过来  祝你明天好运
- Thanks. - Yeah.
- 谢谢  - 嗯
I brought you something.
我给你带了些东西
I hope you don't mind, I took it from the restaurant.
我希望你不要介意  我从餐厅里拿的
- No. - Thanks.
- 没关系  - 谢谢
Adrian.
艾黛丽安
Yeah. Thought she would keep you safe.
是啊  我想她会保佑你平安的
Yeah. Yeah, she always brought me luck.
对  她总给我带来好运
Yeah.
对
I wanted to say thanks for everything you've done for me and my kid.
听着  我想感谢你为我和孩子所做的一切
You've been great and...
你非常棒…
You know, tomorrow...
而明天  你要证明…
...you're gonna prove that the last thing to age on somebody is their heart.
心灵不会随着时间老去的
- I'll try. - You go show them.
- 我尽力  - 证明给他们看
Thank you.
谢谢你
<i>The heavyweight championship</i> <i>has been...</i>
120 年来…
<i>... one of sports' most coveted titles</i> <i>for 120 years.</i>
重量级冠军一直是最为人津津乐道的赛事头衔
<i>Two-time heavyweight champion</i> <i>Rocky Balboa...</i>
两届重量级拳王  洛奇·巴尔博亚
<i>... the Philadelphia slugger,</i> <i>renowned for his cast-iron jaw...</i>
费城重拳手  以其铸铁般的下巴…
<i>... ferocious body attack</i> <i>and will of steel...</i>
凶猛的身体攻击和坚强的意志著称
<i>... all of which have carried</i> <i>the smaller fighter to victories...</i>
所以这些年来  他与比他强大的…
<i>... over the years against</i> <i>physically superior opponents.</i>
…对手对抗  依然屡屡获胜
<i>And Mason Dixon, the current</i> <i>heavyweight title holder...</i>
梅森·迪克逊  现任重量级拳王头衔拥有者
<i>... with all the speed, determination</i> <i>and confidence any fighter could want.</i>
集合了任何一名拳手都想拥有的速度、决心、信心于一身
<i>But many still question whether</i> <i>he has the heart of a true champion...</i>
但是很多人仍然质疑  他是否真的拥有一颗拳王的心
<i>... never having been pushed to go</i> <i>the distance. Tonight, we find out.</i>
怀疑他没有受过真正的考验  今晚  我们将拭目以待
<i>Here at the Mandalay Bay</i> <i>Event Center in Las Vegas...</i>
这里是拉斯维加斯的曼德勒海湾竞技中心
<i>... for the much-anticipated</i> <i>showdown...</i>
万众期待的巅峰之战
<i>... between Mason</i> <i>"The Line" Dixon...</i>
"战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊
<i>... and Rocky</i> <i>"The Italian Stallion" Balboa.</i>
对阵洛奇 "意大利种马" 巴尔博亚
Hello, I'm Jim Lampley with Larry Merchant and Max Kellerman...
大家好  我是吉姆·兰普利
...live from the Mandalay Bay Hotel in Las Vegas, where we anticipate...
在拉斯维加斯的曼德勒海湾酒店向你现场直播…
...one of the most outrageous and compelling events in boxing history.
拳击史上最不寻常的  最令人注目的一场比赛
The unappreciated heavyweight champion, Mason "The Line" Dixon...
现任不被认同的重量级拳王 "战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊
<i>... putting his reputation</i> <i>on the line...</i>
冒险以名誉为赌注
<i>Even though most see this as more</i> <i>of a glorified sparring session...</i>
尽管多数人美其名曰这是一场荣耀的训练赛
...the energy in the room is electric.
但是场中气氛仍很热烈
Larry, why is this billed as an exhibition?
拉里  为什么这场比赛被定义为表演赛？
Wild guess: So they wouldn't have to call it an execution.
我乱猜  他们总不能说这是一场行刑赛吧
Zacariah 4:6 says, "It is not by strength, not by might...
撒迦利亚书 4 章 6 节写道 "不是靠力量  不是靠势力"
...but by his spirit we have already claimed the victory...
"而是靠灵魂  在耶稣之下…"
...in our Lord Jesus Christ."
"我们已经宣称了胜利"
Good luck, Rocky.
好运  洛奇
Thanks, Spider. Appreciate it.
谢谢  斯柏德  我很感激
Nobody's expecting much, I think, from the way-past-his-prime...
没有人会对他抱太大的希望…
...former champ, Rocky Balboa.
年老势衰的洛奇·巴尔博亚
Rock, I gotta talk to you.
洛奇  我有话对你说
Look, I know you got a lot of stuff you gotta get out of your system.
听着  我知道你有很多心事  你必须要全部宣泄出来
Tonight you do it. Right? Get rid of the damn beast...
今晚你就宣泄出来  知道吗？放那头野兽出笼
...let it be done, once and for all. Please, I love you.
放手一搏  一劳永逸  加油  我爱你
<i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i>
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
There go the lights. The buzz is building toward a roaring crescendo.
场内灯光关闭了  观众们的情绪越来越高涨
Where did that come from?
那歌是哪里来的？
I told you. I love Sinatra.
我告诉过你  我喜欢辛纳塔
He's very good, Sinatra.
他很不错  辛纳塔
- Let's go. - Very good.
- 走吧  - 很好
And here comes Rocky Balboa, veteran of the wars...
首先出场的是洛奇·巴尔博亚  沙场老将
...here for one more last hurrah.
最后的表演
Or the Last Supper, perhaps, with him as the main course.
又或是最后的晚餐  他自己就是主菜
What's that music? You can't be serious.
这是什么歌曲？不会吧
"High Hopes"? Talk about wishful thinking.
"远大理想"？讲述的是痴心妄想吧
Well, maybe no hopes is more realistic. Anyway, the crowd likes it.
也许无望更现实  无论怎样  观众喜欢这样
Look at the Italian Stallion. Cool and relaxed.
看看"意大利种马"  很酷很放松
Rocky's an off-the-board underdog, and they don't care at all.
洛奇彻底占下风  但观众们不在乎这个
This is about his pride and dignity and his punch, guys.
这关系到他的骄傲和尊严  还有他的拳头  朋友们
The last thing to go is a guy's punch.
拳手最后的东西就是他的拳头
Rocky always has that puncher's chance.
作为拳手  洛奇总有机会
Rocky Balboa is still, as you can hear, the people's champion.
听得出来  洛奇·巴尔博亚仍然是观众心目中的冠军
Prediction, guys: For at least two rounds...
以我预测  至少前两个回合
...Dixon's gonna have his hands full.
迪克逊要有的忙了
Two whole rounds? We have a cockeyed optimist in the house.
整整两个回合？这儿还有个如此乐观的人
- How you doing? - The crowd wants to see...
- 你好吗？- 观众们想看到…
...something real, or at least...
…真实的比赛  或者至少是…
Rocky Balboa just asked me how I'm doing.
洛奇·巴尔博亚刚刚向我问好了
I grew up watching this guy. I never thought I'd be calling one of his fights.
我可是看着他的拳赛长大的
This is unbelievable. I'm a fan, I can't help it.
太不可思议了  我可是他的拳迷  太激动了
Now here comes Mason Dixon.
梅森·迪克逊来了
Mason Dixon establishing his presence in the ring.
梅森·迪克逊走上了拳台
And suddenly now a conversation breaking out at ringside.
拳台下突然有人跟他对话
Mike Tyson calling out Mason "The Line" Dixon.
迈克·泰森正在呼喊 "战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊的名字
You can't call no shots here. I'm the champ.
这里没你的事  我才是拳王
You not doing nothing. This is charity work.
你干不出什么的  这只是慈善表演
You got that midget with you right there.
你居然和那个老骨头打
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Mandalay Bay...
女士们  先生们  欢迎来到曼德勒海湾赌城…
...resort and casino of Las Vegas.
…度假胜地  拉斯维加斯
And a special main event of the evening...
今晚有一场特殊赛事…
...10 rounds of heavyweight excitement...
由内华达体育委员会批准的…
...sanctioned by the Nevada State Athletic Commission.
十回合的重量级拳赛
And when the bell rings, the referee in charge of the action, Joe Cortez.
本场比赛的裁判是乔·科泰斯
And now, for the thousands in attendance...
现在  在场的成千观众和…
...and the millions watching around the world, ladies and gentlemen...
…上百万的电视机前的观众  先生们  女士们
...let's get ready to rumble!
让我们准备尖叫吧！
Introducing first, fighting out of the blue corner...
首先介绍的是蓝角的…
...wearing black with gold, official weight, 217 pounds.
穿着金黑色短裤的  官方称重 217 磅
His professional record, 57 victories including 54 knockouts...
他的职业纪录为 57 胜 54 次击倒对手获胜
...with 23 defeats and one draw.
23 败 1 次平局
He is the fighting pride of Philadelphia...
他是费城的拳击骄傲
...the two-time heavyweight champion of the world...
两次世界重量级拳王
..."The Italian Stallion"...
"意大利种马"
...Rocky...
洛奇…
...Balboa!
巴尔博亚！
Hope he gets his head busted.
真希望他被打爆头
Shut up.
闭嘴
Across the ring, fighting out of the red corner...
拳台对面红角的…
...wearing white with blue, official weight, 221 pounds.
穿着蓝白色短裤的  官方称重 221 磅
He has a perfect professional record, consisting of 33 bouts...
有着完美的职业纪录  33 战 33 胜
...33 victories, including 30 knockouts.
30 次击倒对手获胜
Originally from Tampa, Florida...
出生于佛罗里达的坦帕
...but now fighting out of Las Vegas, Nevada...
现在在内华达的拉斯维加斯打拳
...the reigning undisputed, undefeated...
无可置疑的统治者  无敌的
...heavyweight champion of the world...
世界重量级拳王
...Mason "The Line"...
"战列步兵"
...Dixon!
梅森·迪克逊！
All right, gentlemen.
好了  先生们
All right, Mason, Rocky. We went over the rules in the dressing room.
梅森  洛奇  在更衣室我们都强调过规则了
I expect a good, clean fight. Watch the kidney punches, rabbit punches...
希望来一场公平正当的较量  不准打肾脏部分或者颈部
...low blows, be careful with those. Give me good sportsmanlike conduct.
不准打下体  要注意这些规则  明白吗？
Remember, gentlemen, I'm fair but I'm firm. Touch them up!
记住  先生们  我既公正又严格  手套互碰！
- Enjoy the ride. - The champ is not in the best shape...
- 享受比赛  - 拳王的状态现在不是最好
...we've seen him in. Maybe he plans to phone this in and go home early.
也许他打算尽快拿下比赛早点回家
- That wouldn't be a surprise. - Glad you could make it.
- 那也不足为奇  - 我爱你 孩子 很高兴你做到了
One thing about Rocky we know for sure:
关于洛奇  我们所知道的有一点是肯定的
This guy's showing up in shape.
这家伙状态不错
- The old man's crazy. - He's gotta be crazy. He's in here.
- 这老家伙一定是疯了  - 他不疯不行 他已经在这里了
- Okay. - Take it easy. This is an exhibition.
- 好的  - 慢慢来 这只是场表演赛
All right? Do it to him.
知道？击倒他
You got three rounds to set a pace. Every time you hit him, make a dent.
你一定要在三局里调整好步伐  每次你击打他后  都后退
- Got it. - The moments before...
- 懂了  - 现在是洛奇·巴尔博亚比赛的前一刻
...a Rocky Balboa fight? I can't believe it's here!
我不敢相信这真的发生了！
Round one begins.
第一回合开始了
If old George Foreman shocked the world with one punch...
如果老乔治·福尔曼  可以一拳震惊这个世界
...why can't old Rocky Balboa?
那为什么老洛奇·巴尔博亚就不可以？
And as much excitement as there is in the arena...
赛场内除了兴奋之外
...there's a sense of foreboding as well.
同样也有种不详的预感
And now, Mason "The Line" Dixon goes to work with his jab as though...
现在  梅森开始用他的刺拳开始攻击
...he's fighting against the number one challenger in the heavyweight division.
尽管他的对手是  重量级领域里的头号挑战者
See, this is to be expected early on.
看  这就是人们预测到会早早上演的
You knew the champ would control the distance with his jab...
早知道拳王会用他的刺拳来压制距离…
...his height, his range.
…压制他的身高和他的臂展
Balboa looking to get in a shot, misses wildly.
巴尔博亚找机会进行了一次攻击  但是完全打偏了
Did you like that?
你喜欢吧？
It looks like a speed bag against a punching bag.
比赛就象是一个速度沙袋对阵一个击打沙袋
Rocky's understandably frustrated...
洛奇开始显出疲态  可以理解
...but he came out of retirement to get into a fight.
但是他复出来参加这场比赛
Guys named Rocky don't like to be toyed with.
洛奇的拥护者不想被愚弄
One punch could still turn it around.
一拳就可以扭转局势
Apparently he forgot his arthritis meds this morning.
显然他今天早上忘了  吃他的关节炎药了
Rocky misses.
洛奇没击中
There's a meat-seeking missile on the point of the chin by the champ.
就像飞弹一样  拳王给对手下巴来了一拳
- More pinpoint jabs by Dixon. - <i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i>
- 迪克逊还是更多的刺拳  - 洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
And there's a hard right hand and a left and a right by Balboa!
巴尔博亚一记右手重拳  又一记左拳  又一记右拳！
He drives Dixon into the ropes with a series of shots!
他一连串的攻击把迪克逊逼到了绳圈处！
And the crowd goes berserk!
观众沸腾了！
Dixon punishing Balboa for the temerity of landing those shots.
迪克逊用一系列攻击来还击巴尔博亚
It's toe to toe in the corner. Balboa and Dixon letting it all go.
双方在绳角处对峙  都放开了打
Balboa landing potent combinations to the head of the champion.
巴尔博亚用组合拳  有效的攻击拳王的头部
A wake-up call for Dixon.
第一回合结束  铃响得很及时对迪克逊来说
- You all right? - Yeah, I'm all right.
- 你还好吗？- 我很好
- The man's got bricks in his gloves. - Where's the stuff in the basement?
- 这老家伙拳套里有砖头  - 你心里的那些闷事呢？
- It's still there. - He came to battle, okay?
- 还在  - 他是来认真比赛的 知道吗？
- Trying to knock me out. - Listen.
- 想击倒我  - 听我说
If there's a bone he can break, he's gonna do it.
如果他一有机会  他肯定会把你的骨头打断的
- Give the man respect. - What about my respect?
- 尊重你的对手  - 那我的自尊呢？
CompuBox numbers tell the grisly story here.
记分系统的比分简直神奇
Balboa landed nine of 13 punches in that round.
这回合巴尔博亚 13 次出拳 9 次击中
Dixon landed an incredible 59 out of 69.
迪克逊不可思议的 69 次出拳 59 次击中
- Why don't you listen to me? - Rocky's been here a million times.
- 你为什么不听我？- 洛奇来过这里无数次了
Coming out to start a round after he took a beating in the previous one.
在经过被动的一回合后  第二回合就要开始了
- Remember what I said, okay? - I warned him. I warned him.
- 记住我说的 知道吗？- 我警告过他 我警告过他
He's tired. His legs are going fast, or already gone.
他累了  他的腿会更快或是已经不行了
And what's truly extraordinary is that Rocky can still take it.
然而真正非凡的就是无论怎样  洛奇还是在继续着
The boxing commission, which was criticized for licensing him...
因发给洛奇拳击执照而备受批评的拳击委员会…
...would be massacred if something happened to Rocky.
…肯定会受到攻击  如果洛奇不幸发生了意外
And a monstrous straight left hand! Down goes Rocky!
好一记左直拳！洛奇倒下了！
And that could conceivably be the end of the fight!
比赛可能就要以令人信服的结果收场！
That could be the exhibition right there. But no. Balboa up.
表演赛到此为止  但是没有  巴尔博亚起来了
Referee Joe Cortez asks if he wants to continue, and Rocky says yes.
裁判科泰斯问他是否要继续比赛  洛奇说继续
Even Rocky Balboa could be too brave for his own good.
就算是洛奇·巴尔博亚  这也未免太勇敢了
Dixon comes right back to try to finish it. Balboa almost went down!
迪克逊迅速回来想就此结束比赛
Rocky actually shoves Dixon back.
洛奇用力把迪克逊推开
As Dixon lands these brutal shots.
而迪克逊出拳更加凶狠
- Cover up! Cover up! - Open shots at close range.
- 护住脸部！护住！- 近距离的攻击
Right and left hands, and down goes Balboa!
右拳  左拳  巴尔博亚倒下了！
Perhaps for the last time in his fighting career!
这也许是他拳击生涯的最后一次了！
- That should do it. - Three! Four!
- 差不多了  - 三！四！
Five! Six!
五！六！
Get up! Get up! - Seven!
- 起来！快起来！- 七！
Eight! Nine!
八！九！
- How do you feel, man? You okay? - Now Rocky is furious with himself.
- 感觉怎样 先生？还好吗？- 现在洛奇发火了
He convinces Cortez he wants to keep fighting.
他说服科泰斯他要继续比赛
Dixon's pointing at the ref to end it.
迪克逊要裁判终止比赛
Rocky waving his arms and saying he's fine.
洛奇挥动他的手臂  说他没事
- He wants to go on! - Let it go! Let it go!
- 他想继续！- 放开打！放开打！
And Balboa comes back! With a left and a right...
巴尔博亚回来了！左右拳交替…
...and bulls Dixon into the ropes for the second round in a row!
第二次把迪克逊逼到了绳圈处！
Back comes Dixon with brutal left-hand shots.
迪克逊用有力的一连串左拳还击
- Dixon hurt his hand there! - Go after him!
- 迪克逊弄伤了手！- 追击他！
This is Rocky's best chance!
这可是洛奇的大好机会！
The champ obviously hurt his hand on Rocky's hip!
很显然拳王在击打洛奇时  弄伤了自己的手！
And Balboa immediately going to work to the body! Huge right hook!
巴尔博亚立即采取了行动  有力的右勾拳！
Balboa ripping away at Dixon's body! These are big punches.
巴尔博亚连续攻击迪克逊的身体！都是些重拳
<i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i>
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
Yes!
好样的！
Rocky Balboa has knocked the reigning heavyweight champion down!
洛奇·巴尔博亚击倒了现任的重量级拳王！
- You hurt him! - Mason "The Line" Dixon...
- 打他！- "战列步兵" 梅森·迪克逊…
...has never taken this kind of punishment...
…在他整个职业生涯中…
...in his entire professional career!
…从没受到过这样的屈辱！
Maybe he's clearing his head, but the body shots really caved in his ribs.
或许他的头部还没中拳  但他的肋骨在重击之下都快碎了
Balboa is thinking knockout himself!
巴尔博亚想着要击倒对手！
Another counterhook by Balboa, followed by two more!
巴尔博亚又一记反勾拳  又是两下！
Dixon fires back his own hooks! Now Rocky's stunned.
迪克逊开始用自己的勾拳还击！现在洛奇有点被打晕了
It's an all-out war along the ropes...
在绳圈处两人展开了殊死搏斗
...as round two comes to a close amid a giant tumult in the ring!
第二回合两人难分高低  在拳台上引起了一阵巨大的骚动！
Incredible.
难以置信
All right!
好！
Welcome to Rockyland.
欢迎来到洛奇的天地
- How's the hand? - My hand's broken.
- 手怎么样了？- 我的手断了
We lose, it's your ass! Your ass!
如果我们输了  你就完蛋了！
It will numb up on you in a few rounds.
等会儿手会麻木的
Once that hand numbs up, Dixon will be able to throw it hard.
手麻木后  迪克逊就可以用力出拳了
Until then, here is Rocky's chance.
但在那之前  是洛奇的机会
- No reverse! - Take the pain, champ.
- 没有退路了  - 挺住！拳王
Stay on him! Everybody thought this was a joke, including me!
保持状态  每个人都以为这是场笑话  包括我！
Now nobody's laughing! Stay on him! You go get him!
但是现在没人会嘲笑了！保持状态！打倒他！
Go out strong!
变得更强壮！
Keep him off you!
不要让他靠近！
That's it! That's it!
就是那样！就是那样！
You won that round. Break him down.
你赢了刚才那个回合  放倒他
Bomb him! Bomb him!
打他！打他！
Yeah!
好！
Just keep throwing them bombs!
继续用力击打他！
Come on.
加油！
You can do this.
你能做到
Rocko. Rocko.
洛奇！洛奇！
Yeah, come on, go!
好  加油  打他！
Go through him! Run over him!
打倒他！放倒他！
Unload on him!
摆脱他！
Get down, Mason!
闪开  梅森！
They're leaving nothing on the table, guys.
双方都使出浑身解数
The fans are still standing. They may not be able to sit down for a week.
拳迷们一直站在那儿  也许他们一周都坐不下来
- You're doing great! - I'm doing better than I thought.
- 你做得很好！- 比我预想的要好
- You sure he's okay? - I've had worse.
- 你肯定他没事？- 我有过更糟糕的
Toe to toe, one round to go. Who would've believed this was possible?
最后一个回合的对峙  谁会想到有这个结果？
- Can you see out of that eye? - Let me talk to him.
- 这个眼睛能看得见吗？- 让我跟他谈
Don't take any more chances than you have to.
如果不行的话  就没必要再继续下去了
There's nothing more to prove, Pop. There's nothing more to prove.
没必要证明更多了  爸爸  没必要证明了
I gotta go out the way I gotta go out.
我会用我的方式完成
You can do it, Rocko!
你会成功的  洛奇！
- One more round, we go home. - Okay, then do it.
- 还有一个回合就回家  - 好 那加油
There's an old saying that every great champion has...
有句老话…
- Come on. Touch them up. - Rocko! The last round of your life!
- 来吧 手套互碰  - 洛奇！这辈子最后一回合了！
- Come on, guys. - The last round!
- 快点 朋友们  - 最后一回合！
Come on. Touch them up, let's go. Touch them up.
来吧  伙计们  手套互碰
- You are one crazy old man. - You'll get there.
- 你是个疯老头  - 你也会老的
Let's go.
开始
Tenth round of a scheduled 10. Who would ever have dreamed...
这已经是第十个回合了  谁能想像得到…
...that Rocky Balboa would still be in this quote, "exhibition," against...
洛奇·巴尔博亚在这场世界重量级冠军的 "表演赛" 中
...the heavyweight champion? - You can do it! Come on!
- 能坚持到这里呢？- 你能行！加油！
This fight is as though Dixon got on-the-job training in courage.
这场拳赛仿佛是对迪克逊进行的在职勇气训练
- Cover up! Cover up! - They're both in a pain-free zone!
- 护着脸！护着脸！- 他们都感觉不到疼了
These guys are fighting in another dimension right now!
这场拳赛现在已经升华到了另一个境界！
Beyond belief! Balboa just walking straight into Dixon's punches.
难以置信！巴尔博亚用正面接受了迪克逊的重拳
Target practice for Dixon.
迪克逊就像是打一个沙袋
They're exchanging right hooks! Balboa's drilled!
双方都用右勾拳相互攻击  巴尔博亚没力气了！
Here comes Dixon! He's exhausted from just punching the man!
迪克逊也没力气了  他连挥拳头的力气都没了！
Knock this bum out, Mase!
打倒这家伙  梅森！
<i>What is it you said to the kid?</i> <i>It ain't about how hard you hit.</i>
你对儿子是怎么说的？你说不在乎强大不强大
<i>It's about how hard you can get hit</i> <i>and keep moving forward.</i>
而是受到打击之后  能否继续向前
<i>How much you can take</i> <i>and keep moving forward.</i>
承受巨大打击  还能勇往直前
- <i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i> - <i>Get up.</i>
- 洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！- 站起来！
- Let's go! Get up! - <i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i>
- 加油！起来！- 洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
<i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i>
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
<i>Get up.</i>
起来！
Another monster body shot. Rocky's ancestors must have felt that one.
又是一记重拳  洛奇肯定被打得灵魂出窍
Come on, Rocky! Start moving those hands!
加油  洛奇！快点出手！
Less than two minutes to go.
还有不到两分钟
The crowd is astonished that Balboa got up.
巴尔博亚站起来了  观众们都震惊了
- Come on! - Turn it over! All the way through!
- 加油！- 扭转局势 彻底打倒他
And retaliates with fury!
开始愤怒的反击！
Chop him down!
打倒他！
Come on, Rocky! Come on!
加油！洛奇！加油！
Take him out now!
击倒他！
They're trading shots again!
双方又开始一系列的相互攻击！
Balboa is trying to hit anything and anywhere!
巴尔博亚不顾一切的进攻！
Win it! Win it!
战胜他！战胜他！
Yes!
好！
You're a great champion. You got heart.
你是个伟大的冠军  你很真诚
Thanks for the opportunity. Good man.
非常感谢 谢谢你给我机会  比赛很棒
That was unbelievable. That was the greatest thing I've ever seen.
太了不起了  这是我见过的最伟大的比赛
You did it. That's the kind of fighting you're talking about.
你做到了  这才是你所说的拳击
Hey, Paulie.
嘿  保利
That beast is gone now. The beast is out.
野兽现在走了  它出笼了
One of the most overused words in sports, guys, is "incredible."
体坛最滥用的词就是 "难以置信"
I hate to say it. This is incredible.
我不得不说  实在是太难以置信了
Let's go!
我们走！
Ladies and gentlemen, before we go to the scorecards...
女士们  先生们  在比分出来之前…
...a round of applause for these two heavyweight warriors!
让我们为这两位重量级勇士鼓掌！
We have a split decision.
裁判产生了点小分歧
Adelaide Byrd scores it 95-94...
阿德莱德·博德  95比94
...Dixon.
迪克逊获胜
Chuck Giampa has it 95-94...
查克·赞帕  95比94
...Balboa.
巴尔博亚获胜
And Bill Graham scores it 95-94...
比尔·葛拉汉姆  95比94
...for the winner by split decision, and still undefeated...
分歧性结果下  世界重量级拳击冠军…
...the heavyweight champion of the world...
仍然是无人能敌的…
...Mason "The Line" Dixon!
梅森·迪克逊！
<i>Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!</i>
洛奇！洛奇！洛奇！
You know, I couldn't have done nothing without you.
没有你我不会成功  艾黛丽安
Yo, Adrian, we did it.
我们做到了
We did it.
做到了